Und behalten Sie Ihren Ruhestand
And keep your retirement
并保留你的退休金
Und Ihre sogenannte Sozialversicherung
And your so-called social security
还有你所谓的社会保障
Große Stadt, lass mich los und befreie mich ...
Big city, turn me loose and set me free...
大城市，放开我，给我自由......
Ich bin Jerry Lundegaard.
I'm Jerry Lundegaard.
我是杰瑞·伦德加德。
Sind Sie Jerry Lundegaard?
You're Jerry Lundegaard?
您是 杰瑞·伦德加德 吗？
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Shep Proudfoot sagte …
Shep Proudfoot said...
Shep Proudfoot 说……
Shep meinte, du wärst um 7:30 hier. Was ist denn los, Mann?
Shep said you'd be here at 7:30.
What gives, man?
谢普说你会在 7:30 到这里。怎么回事啊，老兄？
Shep sagte 8:30.
Shep said 8:30.
谢普说 8:30。
Wir sitzen hier seit einer Stunde.
We've been sitting here an hour.
我们已经在这里坐了一个小时了。
Er hat schon dreimal gepinkelt.
He's peed three times already.
他已经尿了三次了。
Es tut mir wirklich leid. Shep hat mir 8:30 gesagt.
I'm sure sorry.
Shep told me 8:30.
我真的很抱歉。谢普告诉我是 8:30。
Ich schätze, es war eine Verwechslung.
It was a mix-up,
I guess.
我想，这是个混淆。
Hast du das Auto?
You got the car?
你有車嗎？
Ja, darauf kannst du wetten.
Yeah. You bet.
是的，确实如此。
Es steht da draußen auf dem Parkplatz, ein brandneues Cierra in Umbrabraun.
It's out in the lot there, brand-new, burnt umber Cierra.
它就在那片停车场里，崭新，呈焦赭色的 Cierra。
Ja, okay. Dann setz dich.
Yeah, okay.
Well, sit down, then.
好的。那你坐吧。
Ich bin Carl Showalter.
I'm Carl Showalter.
我是卡尔·绍瓦特。
Das ist mein Kollege, Gaear Grimsrud.
This is my associate,
Gaear Grimsrud.
这是我的同事，Gaear Grimsrud。
Ja. Wie geht's?
Yeah. How you doing?
是的。你好吗？
Also, sind wir alle auf diese Sache eingestellt?
So, we all set on this thing, then?
那么，我们都开始做这件事了？
Klar, Jerry. Wir sind startklar. Warum auch nicht?
Sure, Jerry.
We're all set.
Why wouldn't we be?
当然，杰瑞。我们都准备好了。为什么还没准备好呢？
Ja, nein, ich bin sicher, dass Sie das sind.
Yeah, no,
I'm sure you are.
是的，不，我相信你是。
Shep hat für Sie und alle gebürgt.
Shep vouched for you and all.
谢普 (Shep) 为你和大家担保。
Ich habe vollstes Vertrauen in euch, Jungs.
I got every confidence here in you fellas.
我对你们充满信心。
Ich schätze, das war's dann.
I guess that's it, then.
我想就是这样了。
Hier sind die Schlüssel.
Here are the keys.
这是钥匙。
Nein, das ist es nicht, Jerry.
No, that's not it, Jerry.
不，不是这样的，杰瑞。
Hä?
Huh?
嗯？
Das neue Fahrzeug plus 40.000 $.
The new vehicle plus $40,000.
新车另加 40,000 美元。
Ja, aber der Deal war, dass zuerst das Auto kam,
Yeah, but the deal was the car first,
是的，但交易是先买车，
dann die 40.000, als ob es das Lösegeld wäre. then the 40,000, like as if it was the ransom.
然后是 40,000，就好像这是赎金一样。
Ich dachte, Shep hätte es dir erzählt.
I thought Shep told you.
我以为谢普已经告诉你了。
Shep hat uns nicht viel erzählt, Jerry.
Shep didn't tell us much, Jerry.
谢普没有告诉我们太多，杰瑞。
Wir werden, okay ...
We'll, okay...
我们会的，好的...
Außer dass du um 7:30 hier sein würdest.
Except that you were gonna be here at 7:30.
但你本来会在 7:30 到这里。
Ja, also, das war dann eine Verwechslung.
Yeah, well, that was a mix-up, then.
是啊，好吧，那确实是一个混淆。
Ja, das hast du bereits gesagt.
Yeah, you already said that.
是的，你已经这么说了。
Ja, aber es handelt sich nicht um eine Vorauszahlungsvereinbarung.
Yeah, but it's not a whole pay-in-advance deal.
是的，但这并不是一项完全预付款的交易。
Sehen Sie, ich gebe Ihnen im Voraus ein brandneues Fahrzeug und dann ...
See, I give you a brand-new vehicle in advance, and then...
看到吗，我提前给你一辆全新的车，然后……
Ich werde nicht mit dir diskutieren, Jerry.
I'm not gonna debate you, Jerry.
我不想与你辩论，杰瑞。
Okay.
好的。
Ich werde hier nicht sitzen und debattieren.
I'm not gonna sit here and debate.
我不会坐在这里辩论。
Ich werde jedoch Folgendes sagen.
I will say this, though.
但我还是要说一下。
Was Shep uns erzählte, ergab nicht viel Sinn.
What Shep told us didn't make a whole lot of sense.
谢普告诉我们的事情没有多大意义。
Oh nein. Es ist echter Sound. Es ist alles ausgearbeitet.
Oh, no. It's real sound.
It's all worked out.
哦，不。这是真实的声音。一切都已安排好了。
Sie wollen, dass Ihre eigene Frau entführt wird.
You want your own wife kidnapped.
你想让自己的妻子被绑架。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Du...
You...
你...
Was ich sagen will,
My point is,
我的观点是，
Sie zahlen das Lösegeld, was, 80.000 Dollar? you pay the ransom, what, 80,000 bucks?
你支付赎金多少，8 万美元？
Ich meine, Sie geben uns die Hälfte des Lösegelds, 40.000, und Sie behalten die Hälfte.
I mean, you give us half the ransom,
40,000, you keep half.
我的意思是，你给我们一半的赎金，40,000，你留一半。
Es ist, als würde man Peter ausrauben, um Paul zu bezahlen.
It's like robbing
Peter to pay Paul.
这就像是拆东墙补西墙。
Das ergibt keinen Sinn.
It doesn't make any sense.
这没有任何意义。
Okay, sehen Sie, ich bin es nicht, der das Lösegeld bezahlt.
Okay, see, it's not me paying the ransom.
好的，你看，不是我支付赎金。
Die Sache ist, meine Frau ist reich.
The thing is, my wife, she's wealthy.
事实是，我的妻子很富有。
Ihr Vater ist wirklich wohlhabend.
Her dad, he's real well-off.
她的父亲非常富裕。
Jetzt stecke ich in Schwierigkeiten.
Now, I'm in a bit of trouble.
现在我有点麻烦了。
In was für Schwierigkeiten steckst du, Jerry?
What kind of trouble you in, Jerry?
杰瑞，你遇到什么麻烦了？
Nun, das ist... ich werde nicht näher darauf eingehen...
Well, that's...
I'm not gonna get into...
嗯，那是... 我不想谈论...
Sehen Sie, ich brauche nur das Geld.
See, I just need the money.
瞧，我只是需要钱。
Ihr Vater ist wirklich wohlhabend.
Now, her dad, he's real well-off.
如今，她的父亲已经非常富裕了。
Also, warum fragen Sie ihn nicht einfach nach dem Geld?
So, why don't you just ask him for the money?
那么，你为什么不直接向他要钱呢？
Oder deine verdammte Frau, weißt du?
Or your fucking wife, you know?
或者你他妈的老婆，你知道吗？
Oder deine verdammte Frau, Jerry?
Or your fucking wife, Jerry?
或者你的老婆杰瑞？
Also...
Well...
出色地...
Das ist alles Teil davon ...
It's all part of this...
这都是其中的一部分...
Sie wissen nicht, dass ich es brauche, verstehen Sie?
They don't know
I need it, see?
他们不知道我需要它，明白吗？
Okay, das ist es also. Und selbst wenn sie es täten, würde ich es nicht verstehen,
Okay, so there's that.
And even if they did,
I wouldn't get it,
好吧，就是这样。即使他们这么做了，我也不会明白，
das kommt also noch obendrauf. so there's that on top, then.
那么，这就是最上面的内容。
Sehen Sie, das sind persönliche Angelegenheiten.
See, these are personal matters.
瞧，这些都是个人问题。
Persönliche Angelegenheiten?
Personal matters?
个人事务？
Ja, persönliche Angelegenheiten, die nicht …
Yeah, personal matters that needn't...
是啊，个人的事没必要……
Okay, Jerry.
好的，杰瑞。
Sie beauftragen uns mit der Durchführung dieser Mission, aber Sie werden nicht ...
You're tasking us to perform this mission, but you won't...
你委托我们执行这个任务，但是你不愿意......
Das wirst du nicht...
You won't...
你不会...
Scheiß drauf. Schauen wir uns das mal an, Cierra.
Fuck it.
Let's take a look at that Cierra.
管他呢。我们去看看那个 Cierra 吧。
Sie?
Hon?
她？
Hallo, Schatz! Willkommen zurück!
Hi, hon!
Welcome back!
嗨，亲爱的！欢迎回来！
Wie war Fargo?
How was Fargo?
法戈怎么样？
Ja, wirklich gut.
Yeah, real good.
是的，非常好。
Papa ist hier.
Dad's here.
爸爸来了。
...führt die Badgers in diesem Jahr mit fünf Toren an.
...leads the Badgers in goal production with five this year.
...今年以 5 个进球领先獾队。
Wie geht es dir, Wade?
How you doing, Wade?
你好吗，韦德？
Ja, ziemlich gut.
Yeah, pretty good.
是的，非常好。
Was guckst du da?
What you watching there?
你在那看啥？
Taschenratten.
Gophers.
地鼠。
Gegen wen spielen sie?
Who they playing?
他们扮演谁？
Oh!
Ooh!
哦！
Bleibt er dann zum Abendessen?
Is he staying for supper, then?
那么，他会留下来吃晚饭吗？
Ja, ich denke schon.
Yeah. I think so.
是的，我想是的。
- Papa? - Was?
- Dad?
- What?
- 爸爸？ - 什么？
Bleibst du zum Abendessen?
Are you staying for supper?
你留下来吃晚饭吗？
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Darf ich mich entschuldigen?
May I be excused?
我可以原谅吗？
Bist du fertig?
You done there?
你那儿做完了吗？
Mhm. Ich gehe raus.
Uh-huh.
I'm going out.
嗯嗯。我要出去了。
Wo gehst du hin? Einfach raus.
Where are you going?
Just out.
你要去哪儿？刚出来。
Nur McDonald's.
Just McDonald's.
只有麦当劳。
Zurück um 9:30. Okay.
Back at 9:30.
Okay.
9:30 回来。好的。
Er hat gerade gegessen. Er hat nicht aufgegessen.
He just ate.
He didn't finish.
他只是吃了，没吃完。
Gehe zu McDonald's, anstatt hier fertig zu werden.
Going to McDonald's instead of finishing here.
去麦当劳而不是在这里结束。
Er sieht seine Freunde dort. Es ist okay.
He sees his friends there.
It's okay.
他在那里见到了他的朋友。没关系。
Alles okay, McDonald's?
It's okay, McDonald's?
没关系，麦当劳？
Was denkst du, was sie dort machen?
What do you think they do there?
你认为他们在那儿做什么？
Sie trinken keine Milchshakes, das versichere ich Ihnen.
They don't drink milk shakes,
I assure you.
我向你保证，他们不喝奶昔。
Es ist okay, Papa.
It's okay, Dad.
没关系，爸爸。
Wade, hatten Sie Gelegenheit, darüber nachzudenken,
Wade, have you had a chance to think about
韦德，你有没有想过
der Deal, von dem ich gesprochen habe, that deal I was talking about,
我之前谈到的那笔交易
diese 40 Morgen dort in Wayzata? those 40 acres there, in Wayzata?
韦扎塔那边的 40 英亩土地吗？
Du hast mir davon erzählt.
You told me about it.
你告诉过我这件事。
Ja, Sie sagten, Sie müssten darüber nachdenken.
Yeah, you said you'd have to think about it.
是的，你说过你必须考虑一下。
Ich verstehe. Es ist viel Geld.
I understand.
It's a lot of money.
我明白。这是一大笔钱。
Das ist verdammt viel. Was wolltest du da noch alles hinstellen?
It's a heck of a lot.
What did you say you were gonna put there?
数量可不少。你之前说要放些什么进去？
Sehr viel. Es ist ein...
A lot. It's a...
很多。这是...
Ich weiß, es ist viel.
I know it's a lot.
我知道这很多。
Ich meine einen Parkplatz.
I mean a parking lot.
我指的是停车场。
Nun, 750.000 ist eine Menge.
Well, 750,000 is a lot.
嗯，75万是不少。
Ja, also, es ist ein Brocken, aber …
Yeah, well, it's a chunk, but...
是啊，嗯，是一大块，但是......
Ich hatte ein paar Lose, Ende 503. Habe viel Geld verloren.
I had a couple lots, late 503.
Lost a lot of money.
我有几批货，503 已过期。损失了很多钱。
Viel Geld. Ja. Aber der Unterschied ...
A lot of money.
Yeah. but the difference...
很多钱。是的。但是差别...
Ich dachte, du würdest es Stan Grossman zeigen.
I thought you were gonna show it to Stan Grossman.
我以为你要把它展示给斯坦·格罗斯曼。
Er gibt das Zeug weiter, bevor es an mich weitergeleitet wird.
He passes on this stuff before it gets kicked up to me.
在他把这些东西传给我之前，他就把这些东西传给了我。
Nun, Stan wird sagen: „Keine Chance.“ Dafür bezahlen Sie ihn.
Well, Stan'll say, "No dice."
That's why you pay him.
那么，斯坦会说，“没戏。”这就是你付钱给他的原因。
Ich frage dich hier, Wade.
I'm asking you here, Wade.
我在这里问你，韦德。
Das könnte für mich, Jean und Scotty wirklich gut ausgehen.
This could work out real good for me and Jean and Scotty.
这对我、Jean 和 Scotty 来说都是非常好的事情。
Jean und Scotty müssen sich nie Sorgen machen.
Jean and Scotty never have to worry.
Jean 和 Scotty 永远不需要担心。
Wo ist das Pancakes House?
Where is Pancakes House?
煎饼屋位于何处？
Was?
What?
什么？
Wir halten am Pancakes House.
We stop at Pancakes House.
我们在 Pancakes House 停留。
Bist du verrückt? Wir hatten Pfannkuchen zum Frühstück.
What are you, nuts?
We had pancakes for breakfast.
你疯了吗？我们早餐吃煎饼。
Ich muss an einen Ort gehen, wo ich eine Spritze bekommen kann
Gotta go to a place where I can get a shot
我得去一个可以打针的地方
und vielleicht ein Bier und ein Steak. and a beer and a steak, maybe.
也许，还可以加一杯啤酒和一份牛排。
Keine verdammten Pfannkuchen mehr. Komm schon.
Not more fucking pancakes.
Come on.
不要再吃他妈的煎饼了。来吧。
Ach, komm schon, Mann.
Oh, come on, man.
噢，拜托，哥们。
Okay. Hier ist eine Idee.
Okay. Here's an idea.
好的。我有个主意。
Wir können außerhalb von Brainerd anhalten.
We can stop outside of Brainerd.
我们可以在布雷纳德外面停留。
Ich kenne da einen Ort, wo wir Sex haben können. Was meinst du?
I know a place there where we can get laid.
What do you think?
我知道一个我们可以做爱的地方。你觉得怎么样？
Ich habe jetzt verdammten Hunger, weißt du.
I'm fucking hungry now, you know.
你知道吗，我现在饿极了。
Ja, ja, Jesus. Ich sage, wir können anhalten und Pfannkuchen holen.
Yeah, yeah, Jesus.
I'm saying we can stop, get pancakes,
是的，是的，耶稣。我说我们可以停下来，吃煎饼，
und dann haben wir Sex, okay? and then we'll get laid, all right?
然后我们就做爱，好吗？
Lou Diamond, Zeile eins.
Lou Diamond, line one.
卢·戴蒙德，第一行。
Wir saßen genau hier in diesem Raum
We sat right here in this room
我们就坐在这个房间里
und ging dies und das durch. and went over this and over this.
并反复研究这一点。
Ja, aber dieser TruCoat ...
Yeah, but that TruCoat...
是的，但是那个 TruCoat...
Ich saß hier und sagte, ich wollte kein TruCoat.
I sat right here and said I didn't want any TruCoat.
我坐在这里说我不想要任何 TruCoat。
Ja, aber das sage ich, TruCoat.
Yeah, but I'm saying that TruCoat.
是的，但我说的是 TruCoat。
Wenn Sie es nicht bekommen, bekommen Sie Oxidationsprobleme.
You don't get it, you get oxidation problems.
你不明白，你遇到的是氧化问题。
Es wird Sie viel mehr als 500 $ kosten.
It'll cost you a heck of a lot more than $500.
这会花费你远远超过 500 美元的钱。
Du sitzt da.
You're sitting there.
你就坐在那儿。
Sie reden im Kreis.
You're talking in circles.
你在绕圈子说话。
Sie reden, als hätten wir das nicht schon besprochen.
You're talking like we didn't go over this already.
你说话的样子好像我们还没有讨论过这个问题。
Ja, aber dieser TruCoat ...
Yeah, but this TruCoat...
是的，但是这个 TruCoat...
Wir hatten hier einen Deal über 19.500.
We had a deal here for 19,500.
我们在这里达成了 19,500 的交易。
Du saßt da und verdammt, wenn du es mir nicht gesagt hättest
You sat there and darned if you didn't tell me
你坐在那里，如果你不告诉我
Du würdest mir dieses Auto besorgen, diese Optionen, you'd get me this car, these options,
你会给我买这辆车，这些选择，
ohne Versiegelung für 19.500. without the sealant, for 19,500.
不含密封剂，售价19,500美元。
Okay, ich sage nicht, dass ich das nicht getan habe.
All right,
I'm not saying I didn't.
好吧，我不是说我没有。
Du hast mich vor 20 Minuten angerufen und gesagt
You called me
20 minutes ago and said
20 分钟前你打电话给我说
Sie hatten es zur Auslieferung bereit. you had it ready to make delivery.
您已准备好发货。
Sie sagen: „Kommen Sie runter und holen Sie es sich.“
You says,
"Come on down and get it."
你说：“快下来拿来。”
Und hier sind Sie und verschwenden meine Zeit und die Zeit meiner Frau.
And here you are, and you're wasting my time and my wife's time,
你在这里，浪费我和我妻子的时间，
und ich zahle 19.500 für dieses Fahrzeug hier. and I'm paying 19,500 for this vehicle here.
我为这辆车付了 19,500 美元。
In Ordnung.
All right.
好的。
Ich werde mit meinem Chef sprechen.
I'll talk to my boss.
我要和我的老板谈谈。
Sehen Sie, sie installieren TruCoat im Werk.
See. they Install that TruCoat at the factory.
看，他们在工厂安装了 TruCoat。
Wir können nichts tun, aber ich werde mit meinem Chef sprechen.
There's nothing we can do, but I'll talk to my boss.
我们无能为力，但是我会和我的老板谈谈。
Diese Typen hier. Diese Typen.
These guys here.
These guys.
这些人在这里。这些人。
Es ist immer das Gleiche. Es ist immer mehr.
It's always the same.
It's always more.
总是一样，总是更多。
Gehst du am Sonntag zu den Gophers?
You going to the Gophers on Sunday?
你星期天要去看 Gophers 吗？
Oh, darauf kannst du wetten.
Oh, you betcha.
噢，那当然了。
Sie hätten kein zusätzliches Ticket?
You wouldn't have an extra ticket?
您没有多余的票吗？
Machst du Witze?
You kidding?
你在开玩笑吧？
Also,
Well,
出色地，
er hat das noch nie getan, he never done this before,
他以前从来没有这样做过，
aber da es besondere Umstände sind und so. but seeing as
It's special circumstances and all.
但鉴于这是特殊情况。
Er sagt, ich könnte den TruCoat um 100 $ reduzieren.
He says I can knock
$100 off that TruCoat.
他说我可以将 TruCoat 的价格降低 100 美元。
100?
100？
Sie haben mich angelogen, Herr Lundegaard.
You lied to me,
Mr. Lundegaard.
你对我撒了谎，伦德加德先生。
Sie sind ein dreister Lügner.
You're a bald-faced liar.
你真是个厚颜无耻的骗子。
Bucky, bitte.
Bucky, please.
巴基，求你了。
Ein verdammter Lügner.
A fucking liar.
他妈的骗子。
Bucky, bitte.
Bucky, please.
巴基，求你了。
Wo ist mein verdammtes Scheckbuch?
Where's my goddamn checkbook?
我的支票簿在哪儿？
Bringen wir es hinter uns.
Let's get this over with.
让我们把这件事解决掉吧。
Wo ist es?
Where is it?
它在哪里？
Aus Hollywood: „The Tonight Show“ mit …
From Hollywood,
The Tonight Show, starring...
来自好莱坞的《今夜秀》，主演......
Ich spreche über Ihr Potenzial.
I am talking about your potential.
我正在谈论你的潜力。
Mmm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Du bist kein durchschnittlicher Schüler.
You're not a C student.
你不是一个 C 级学生。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Trotzdem bekommen Sie die Note C.
Yet you're getting
C grades.
但你的成绩却只有 C。
Es ist diese Ungleichheit, die deinem Vater und mir Sorgen bereitet.
It's that disparity there that concerns your dad and me.
正是这种差异令你父亲和我感到担忧。
Mh-hm.
Uh-huh.
嗯嗯。
Wissen Sie, was eine Ungleichheit ist?
You know what a disparity is?
你知道什么是差距吗？
Ja!
Yeah!
是的！
Okay! Nun, deshalb haben wir...
Okay! Well, that's why we...
好的！嗯，这就是为什么我们...
Wir wollen nicht, dass Sie zum Hockey gehen.
We don't want you going out for hockey.
我们不希望你出去打曲棍球。
Oh Mann!
Oh, man!
噢，伙计！
Komm schon. Was ist denn so schlimm? Es ist nur eine Stunde ...
Come on.
What's the big deal?
It's just an hour...
拜托。有什么大不了的？只是一个小时……
Festhalten.
Hold on.
坚持，稍等。
Was ist die große Sache?
What's the big deal?
有什么大不了的？
Hallo?
Hello?
你好？
Ja, hallo, Schatz. Oh, hallo, Papa.
Yeah, hiya, hon.
Oh. hi. Dad.
是的，你好，亲爱的。噢，你好，爸爸。
Ist Jerry da?
Is Jerry around?
傑瑞在嗎？
Ja, Schatz! Ja, er ist hier.
Yeah. Hon!
Yeah, he's here.
是的。亲爱的！是的，他在这里。
Ja, ich werde ihn für dich fangen.
Yeah, I'll catch him for you.
是啊，我会帮你抓住他的。
- Schatz! - Ja?
- Hon!
- Yeah?
- 亲爱的！- 什么事？
Okay. Hier ist Papa.
Okay.
It's Dad.
好的。我是爸爸。
Hör zu, Dad, das ist verdammt nochmal unmöglich ...
Look, Dad, there's no fucking way...
瞧，爸爸，这他妈的不可能……
Scotty!
斯科蒂！
Hey, lasst uns auf die Sprache dort achten.
Hey, let's watch that language there.
嘿，让我们看看那里的语言。
Wie geht es dir, Wade?
How you doing there, Wade?
你好吗，韦德？
Was ist da los?
What's going on there?
那儿发生什么事了？
Nichts, Wade. Wie geht es dir?
Nothing, Wade.
How you doing there?
没什么，韦德。你在那里怎么样？
Stan Grossman hat sich Ihren Vorschlag angesehen.
Stan Grossman looked at your proposal.
斯坦·格罗斯曼看了你的提议。
Er sagt, es ist ziemlich süß.
He says it's pretty sweet.
他说这很甜。
Kein Scherz?
No kidding?
没开玩笑吧？
Könnte interessant sein.
Might be interested.
可能会感兴趣。
Kein Scherz? Da bräuchte ich das Geld ziemlich schnell,
No kidding?
I'd need the cash pretty quick there,
开玩笑吧？我当时急需现金，
um den Deal abzuschließen. in order to close the deal.
以达成交易。
Komm um 14:30 Uhr vorbei. Wir reden darüber.
Come by at 2:30.
We 'll talk about it.
2:30 过来。我们会讨论这件事。
Wenn Ihre Zahlen stimmen, sagt Stan, ist es ziemlich cool.
If your numbers are right, Stan says it's pretty sweet.
如果您的数字正确，斯坦说这真是太好了。
Stan, du weißt schon, Grossman. Ja.
Stan. you know. Grossman.
Yeah.
斯坦，你知道的。格罗斯曼，是的。
2:30 Uhr.
2:30.
2:30。
Ja. Okay.
Yeah. Okay.
嗯，好的。
Sag mal, Shep, wie geht es dir da?
Say, Shep, how you doing there?
说吧，谢普，你在那里怎么样？
Sag mal, kennst du diese beiden Kerle?
Say, you know those two fellas
你知道那两个家伙吗
Sie haben den Kontakt zu denen dort oben in Fargo hergestellt? you put me in touch with up there in Fargo?
你能帮我联系法戈那边吗？
Ich habe Sie mit Grimsrud in Kontakt gebracht.
I put you in touch with Grimsrud.
我让你和格里姆斯鲁德取得联系。
Ja, er hatte dort einen Kumpel.
Yeah, well, he had a buddy there.
是的，他在那里有一个朋友。
Dann kann ich nicht für ihn bürgen.
Then I don't vouch for him.
那我就不为他担保。
Nun, das ist okay.
Well, that's okay.
嗯，没关系。
Ich bürge für Grimsrud. Wer ist sein Kumpel?
I vouch for Grimsrud.
Who's his buddy?
我为 Grimsrud 担保。他的朋友是谁？
Carl irgendwas.
Carl something.
卡尔什么的。
Ich habe noch nie von ihm gehört. Ich kann nicht für ihn bürgen.
Never heard of him.
Don't vouch for him.
从未听说过他。不要为他担保。
Na, das ist okay. Er ist ein Kumpel von dem Kerl, für den du gebürgt hast.
Well, that's okay.
He's a buddy of the guy you vouched for,
好吧，没关系。他是你担保的人的朋友，
also mache ich mir keine Sorgen. Ich ... so I'm not worried.
I just...
所以我不担心。我只是……
Ich habe mich gefragt, ob ich mit ihm Kontakt aufnehmen kann.
I was wondering, see, I got to get in touch with him.
我在想，看，我必须和他取得联系。
Sehen Sie, diesen Deal, für den ich ihn brauchte, brauche ich vielleicht nicht mehr.
See, this deal I needed him for, I may not need it anymore.
瞧，我需要他达成的这笔交易，现在我可能不再需要他了。
Da ist was los. Siehst du? Ruf ihn an.
Something's happening. see.
Call him up.
有事发生。瞧。给他打电话。
Ja, also, sehen Sie, das habe ich getan, und ich konnte ihn nicht erreichen,
Yeah, well, see, I did that, and I haven't been able to get him,
是的，我这么做了，但我没能得到他，
also dachte ich, Sie kennen vielleicht eine andere Nummer oder so. so I thought maybe you'd know an alternate number, or what have you.
所以我想也许你知道另一个号码，或者其他什么。
Nein.
Nope.
没有。
Okay. Also...
Okay. Well...
好的。嗯...
Also wirklich gut.
Real good, then.
那么，真的很好。
Kannst du ein verdammtes Fenster einen Spalt aufmachen, Mann?
Can you crack a fucking window open, man?
你能把窗户打开吗，伙计？
Wissen Sie, es ist erwiesen, dass Passivrauchen ...
You know, it's proven that secondhand smoke is...
你知道，事实证明二手烟是……
Sie wissen schon, ein Krebsmittel.
You know, a cancer agent.
你知道的，一种致癌剂。
Hey, sieh dir das an. Twin Cities.
Hey, look at that.
Twin Cities.
嘿，看那边。双城。
Das ist das IDS-Gebäude, das große aus Glas.
That's the IDS Building, the big glass one.
那是IDS大楼，巨大的玻璃大楼。
Höchster Wolkenkratzer im Mittleren Westen nach dem Sears in Chicago,
Tallest skyscraper in the Midwest after the Sears in Chicago,
继芝加哥西尔斯大厦之后中西部最高的摩天大楼，
oder das John Hancock-Gebäude, was auch immer. or John Hancock building, whatever.
或者约翰汉考克大厦，随便什么。
Waren Sie schon einmal in Minneapolis?
You ever been to Minneapolis?
你去过明尼阿波利斯吗？
NEIN.
No.
不。
Würde es dich umbringen, etwas zu sagen?
Would it kill you to say something?
你说了什么就会死吗？
Das habe ich.
I did.
是的。
„Nein.“ Das ist das Erste, was Sie in den letzten vier Stunden gesagt haben.
"No." That's the first thing you've said in the last four hours.
“不。”这是过去四个小时里你说的第一句话。
Das ist ein...
That's a...
那是一个...
Das ist ein echter Gesprächsstoff, Mann.
That's a fountain of conversation, man.
这真是一个谈话的源泉，伙计。
Das ist ein Geysir.
That's a geyser.
那是间歇泉。
Ich meine, bleib stehen, Daddy. Bleib zurück, Mann.
I mean, whoa, daddy.
Stand back, man.
我的意思是，哇哦，爸爸。往后退，老兄。
Scheiße.
Shit.
拉屎。
Ich sitze hier und fahre.
I'm sitting here driving.
我坐在这里开车。
Ich fahre die ganze Zeit, Mann,
I'm doing all the driving, man,
我全程开车，哥们
den ganzen verdammten Weg von Brainerd, mit dem Auto. whole fucking way from Brainerd, driving.
从布雷纳德一路开车过来。
Ich versuche nur zu chatten.
Just trying to chat.
只是想聊天。
Weißt du, halte unsere Stimmung aufrecht,
You know, keep our spirits up,
你知道，让我们保持精神振奋，
bekämpfe die Langeweile der Straße, fight the boredom of the road,
对抗路上的无聊，
und du kannst während eines Gesprächs nicht ein einziges verdammtes Wort sagen? and you can't say one fucking thing just in the way of conversation?
在谈话中你连一句话都不能说吗？
Ach, scheiß drauf. Ich muss auch nicht reden, Mann.
Oh, fuck it. I don't have to talk either, man.
哦，去他妈的。我也不需要说话，哥们。
Schauen Sie, wie es Ihnen gefällt.
See how you like it.
看看你是否喜欢。
Einfach nur totale, verdammte Stille.
Just total fucking silence.
只是一片寂静。
Dieses Spiel könnten zwei spielen, kluger Kerl.
Two could play at that game, smart guy.
两个人可以玩这个游戏，聪明的家伙。
Wir werden einfach sehen, wie es Ihnen gefällt.
We'll just see how you like it.
我们只是想看看你是否喜欢它。
Absolute Stille.
Total silence.
一片寂静。
Herr Lundegaard, hier ist Reilly Diefenbach von GMAC.
Mr. Lundegaard, this is Reilly
Diefenbach from GMAC.
伦德加德先生，这是 GMAC 的赖利·迪芬巴赫。
Wie geht es Ihnen heute Morgen?
How are you this morning?
你今天早上好嗎？
Echt gut. Wie geht's?
Real good.
How you doing?
非常好。你好吗？
Ziemlich gut, Herr Lundegaard.
Pretty good,
Mr. Lundegaard.
非常好，伦德加德先生。
Es ist verdammt schwer, dich ans Telefon zu bekommen.
You're damn hard to get on the phone.
你打电话真难接。
Hier ist verdammt viel los, aber so mögen wir es.
It's pretty darn busy here, but that's the way we like it.
这里确实很繁忙，但我们喜欢这样。
Nun, das ist sicher.
Well, that's for sure.
嗯，这是肯定的。
Jetzt muss ich nur noch diese letzten,
Now, I just need on these last,
现在我只需要最后这些，
diese Finanzierungsunterlagen, die Sie uns zugesandt haben, these financing documents that you sent us,
您发送给我们的这些融资文件，
Ich kann die Seriennummern der Fahrzeuge nicht lesen.
I can't read the serial numbers of the vehicles.
我读不懂车辆的序列号。
Ja, aber ich habe schon das ...
Yeah, but I already got the...
是啊，不过我已经得到了...
Es ist okay. Die Kredite sind vorhanden.
It's okay.
The loans are in place.
没事，贷款已经到账了。
Ich habe schon das... Was? Das...
I already got the...
What? The...
我已经得到了...什么？那个...
Ja, die 320.000.
Yeah, the 320,000.
是的，32万。
Sie haben das Geld letzten Monat bekommen.
You got the money last month.
你上个月收到的钱。
Ja, dann sind wir also startklar.
Yeah, so we're all set, then.
好的，那么我们就一切就绪了。
Ja, aber die Fahrzeuge, für die Sie Kredite aufnehmen.
Yeah. but the vehicles that you're borrowing on.
是的。但是你借的是车辆。
[Ich kann die Seriennummern Ihrer Anwendung einfach nicht lesen.
[just can't read the serial numbers on your application.
[只是无法读取您应用程序上的序列号。
Vielleicht, wenn Sie einfach lesen könnten ...
Maybe if you could just read...
也许如果你能读一读……
Ja, aber der Deal ist bereits abgeschlossen.
Yeah, but the deal's already done.
是的，但是交易已经完成了。
Ich habe das Geld bereits bekommen.
I already got the money.
我已经收到钱了。
Ja, aber wenn wir hier eine Prüfung haben,
Yes, but if we have an audit here,
是的，但如果我们在这里进行审计，
[man muss nur wissen, dass diese Fahrzeuge
[just have to know that these vehicles
[只需知道这些车辆
Sie finanzieren mit diesem Geld, you're financing with this money,
你用这笔钱融资，
dass sie wirklich existieren. that they really exist.
它们确实存在。
Ja, also, es gibt sie, ganz genau.
Yeah, well, they exist, all right.
是的，它们确实存在。
Ich bin sicher, dass sie das tun.
I'm sure they do,
我相信他们会的，
aber ich kann die Seriennummern hier nicht lesen, also wenn Sie mir das vorlesen könnten ... but I can't read the serial numbers here, so if you could read me...
但我无法在这里读出序列号，所以如果你能读懂我的话……
Ja, aber... sehen Sie...
Yeah, but... See...
是啊，但是...看...
Ich habe sie nicht vor mir.
I don't have them in front of me.
我面前没有它们。
Warum faxe ich Ihnen nicht einfach eine Kopie?
Why don't I just fax you over a copy?
我何不直接传真一份给你呢？
Nein, also nein, Faxen ist nicht gut.
No, well, no, fax is no good.
不，不，传真没什么用。
Das ist, was ich habe, und ich kann das verdammte Ding nicht lesen.
That's what I have, and I can't read the darn thing.
这就是我所拥有的，但我读不懂这个该死的东西。
Ja, okay. Dann lasse ich dir von meiner Freundin eine Kopie schicken.
Yeah, okay. I'll have my girl send you a copy, then.
好的。那我就让我女儿给你寄一份吧。
Okay, denn wenn ich diese Notiz nicht mit den spezifischen Fahrzeugen in Verbindung bringen kann,
Okay, because if
I can't correlate this note with the specific vehicles,
好吧，如果我不能把这张纸条和具体车辆联系起来，
dann muss ich das Geld zurückfordern. then I got to call back that money.
然后我就得把那笔钱取回来。
Ja, wie viel Geld war das?
Yeah, how much money was that?
是啊，那是多少钱？
320.000. Ich muss dieses Geld korrelieren
320,000.
I got to correlate that money
32万。我得把这笔钱关联起来
mit den Autos, für die es verliehen wird. with the cars it's being lent on.
以及借出的汽车。
Ja. Okay. Kein Problem. Ich faxe das gleich rüber.
Yeah. Okay. no problem.
I'll just fax that right over.
是的。好的。没问题。我马上就传真过来。
Nein, nein, nein. Fax...
No, no, no. Fax...
不不不。传真……
Ich meine, schick es rüber. Ich schicke es dir dann gleich rüber.
I mean, send it over.
I'll shoot it right over to you, then.
我的意思是，把它发过来。然后我会马上把它发给你。
Okay, okay. Gut.
Okay, okay. Fine.
好的，好的。很好。
Okay. Also wirklich gut.
Okay. Real good, then.
好的。那么，真的很棒。
Wir sind zurück mit Katie Carlson. Hallo.
We're back with Katie Carlson.
Hi.
我们又和凯蒂·卡尔森见面了。嗨。
Bevor wir jetzt loslegen,
Now, before we get going here,
现在，在我们开始之前，
Wir möchten alle unsere Zuschauer zu Hause daran erinnern we just want to remind all of our viewers at home
我们只是想提醒所有在家的观众
dass diesen März zum zweiten Mal in Folge that this March, for the second year in a row,
今年三月，连续第二年，
Katie und ich, zusammen mit Twin City Travel,
Katie and I, along with
Twin City Travel,
凯蒂和我以及 Twin City Travel，
wird eine zweiwöchige Flussschifffahrt auf dem Nil leiten. will be leading a two-week riverboat trip down the Nile.
将带领游客进行为期两周的尼罗河游船之旅。
Es ist eine tolle Zeit. Ich weiß, Sie haben davon gehört.
It's a terrific time.
I know you've heard about it.
这是一个非常棒的时刻。我知道你已经听说了。
Wir möchten, dass Sie alle mitkommen,
We want all of you to come with,
我们希望你们都来，
und das ist die Wahrheit. and that's the truth.
这确实是事实。
Okay, für diejenigen unter Ihnen, die gerade erst zu uns gestoßen sind,
Okay, now, for those of you that just joined us,
好的，现在，对于刚刚加入我们的人，
Katie wird uns heute Morgen zeigen
Katie here, this morning, is going to show us
今天早上，凯蒂将向我们展示
So machen Sie selbst Holidazzle-Eier zu Hause. how to make
Holidazzle eggs ourselves, at home.
如何在家自己制作 Holidazzle 鸡蛋。
Was? Jetzt. Katie. Ich muss zugeben...
What?
Now. Katie. I gotta admit...
什么？现在。凯蒂。我得承认……
Ich war ein wenig überrascht, als ich es zum ersten Mal in die Hand nahm.
I was a little bit surprised when I first picked this up.
当我第一次拿起这个的时候我有点惊讶。
Rechts.
Right.
正确的。
Dies ist ein leeres Ei.
This is an empty egg.
这是一个空蛋。
Das stimmt, Dale.
That's right, Dale.
没错，戴尔。
Also, wie bekommt man das Ei...
Well, how do you get the egg...
那么，你如何得到鸡蛋呢......
Ja. Das Thema hier war ein Ei, richtig?
Yeah.
Theme was an egg in here. right?
是的。主题是一颗鸡蛋。对吧？
Okay, also, ich weiß nicht... Wie geht es dir... Ich meine, du hast nicht
Okay, well, I don't...
How do you...
I mean, you don't have
好吧，我不知道……你怎么……我的意思是，你没有
ein leeres Huhn irgendwo, das leere Eier legt? an empty chicken somewhere that lays empty eggs?
某处有一只空鸡，下着空蛋？
Nein, nein.
No, no.
不不。
Ich garantiere, das war ein ehrlicher...
I guarantee, this was an honest-to-goodness...
我保证，这是一次货真价实的……
Salbe
Unguent
软膏
Was?
What?
什么？
Ich brauche Salbe.
I need unguent.
我需要油膏。
NEIN.
No.
不。
NEIN...
No...
不...
Du willst es tun?
You want to do it?
你想做吗？
Drücken.
Push.
推。
Wie geht es dir, Stan? Wie geht es dir, Wade?
How are you, Stan?
How you doing, Wade?
你好吗，斯坦？你好吗，韦德？
Schön, dich wiederzusehen, Jerry.
Good to see you again, Jerry.
很高兴再次见到你，杰瑞。
Wenn diese Zahlen stimmen, sieht das ziemlich gut aus.
If these numbers are right, this looks pretty sweet.
如果这些数字正确的话，这看起来相当不错。
Diese Zahlen stimmen, ganz genau.
Those numbers are right, all right.
这些数字是正确的，没错。
Glauben Sie mir.
Believe me.
相信我。
Das ist machbar.
This is doable.
这是可行的。
Herzlichen Glückwunsch, Jer.
Congratulations, Jer.
恭喜你，杰尔。
Ja, danke, Stan. Also, es ist ziemlich ...
Yeah, thanks, Stan.
Well, it's a pretty...
是的，谢谢，斯坦。嗯，这很美……
Nach welcher Art von Finderlohn haben Sie gesucht?
What kind of finder's fee were you looking for?
您寻求的是怎样的中介费？
Hä?
Huh?
嗯？
Die Finanzdaten sind ziemlich gründlich,
The financials are pretty thorough,
财务数据相当详尽，
Das Einzige, was wir nicht wissen, ist Ihr Honorar. so the only thing we don't know is your fee.
所以我们唯一不知道的就是您的费用。
Mein Honorar?
My fee?
我的费用？
Wade, wovon zum Teufel redest du?
Wade, what the heck are you talking about?
韦德，你到底在说什么？
Stan und mir geht es gut.
Stan and I are okay.
斯坦和我都很好。
Ja. Wir können gleich einladen.
Yeah.
We're good to load In.
好的。我们可以装载了。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Aber wir haben nie über Ihr Honorar für die Übergabe gesprochen.
But we never talked about your fee for bringing it to us.
但我们从未谈论过您将其带给我们的费用。
Nein, aber, Wade, sehen Sie, ich habe Ihnen dieses Angebot gemacht
No, but, Wade, see,
I was bringing you this deal
不，但是，韦德，你看，我正给你带来这笔交易
damit du mir das Geld leihst, das ich investieren kann. for you to loan me the money to put in.
请你借钱给我投入。
Das ist mein Deal hier, verstehen Sie?
It's my deal here, see.
这是我的交易，明白了吗。
Jerry, wir dachten, Sie würden uns eine Investition bringen.
Jerry, we thought you were bringing us an investment.
杰瑞，我们以为你会给我们带来一笔投资。
Ja, genau.
Yeah. Right.
是啊。没错。
Sie sagen...
You're saying...
你是说...
Was sagst du?
What are you saying?
你在说什么？
Sie sagen, wir hätten das ganze Geld investiert,
You're saying we put in all the money,
你是说我们投入了所有的钱，
und Sie kassieren, wenn es sich auszahlt. and you collect when it pays off.
当它产生效益时，您就可以收款。
Nein, nein. Siehst du... Aber ich würde...
No, no. See... But I'd...
不，不。你看...但是我会...
Ich würde Ihnen den Kapitalbetrag und die Zinsen zurückzahlen.
I'd pay you back the principal and interest.
我会还你本金和利息。
Verdammt, ich würde noch einen draufsetzen?
Heck, I'd go one over prime?
哎呀，我会比 Prime 更胜一筹吗？
Wir sind keine Bank, Jerry.
We're not a bank, Jerry.
我们不是银行，杰瑞。
Wenn ich Bankzinsen auf 750.000 wollte,
If I wanted bank interest on 750,000,
如果我想要75万的银行利息，
Ich würde zu Midwest Federal gehen und mit dem alten Bill Diehl sprechen.
I'd go to Midwest Federal, talk to old Bill Diehl.
我要去中西部联邦，和老比尔·迪尔谈谈。
Er ist bei North Star. Er ist bei ...
He's at North Star.
He's at...
他在北极星。他在……
Nein, nein. Siehe, Lu
No, no. See, Lu
不不。瞧，卢
Ich brauche kein Finderlohn. Ich brauche …
I don't need a finder's fee.
I need...
我不需要中介费。我需要……
Die Findergebühr beträgt, was, 10 %?
Finder's fee is, what, 10%?
中介费是多少，10%？
Verdammt, das wird mir nichts bringen.
Heck, that's not gonna do it for me.
哎呀，这对我没用。
Ich brauche den Direktor.
I need the principal.
我需要校长。
Also, Jerry, wir werden Ihnen nicht einfach 750.000 Dollar geben.
Well, Jerry, we're not gonna just give you $750,000.
好吧，杰瑞，我们不会只给你 75 万美元。
Was zum Teufel hast du dir dabei gedacht?
What the heck were you thinking?
你到底在想什么？
Wenn ich nur Bankzinsen bekomme,
If I'm only getting bank interest,
如果我只得到银行利息，
Ich will absolute Sicherheit. Zum Teufel, FDIC.
I want complete security.
Heck, FDIC.
我想要完全的安全。哎呀，联邦存款保险公司 (FDIC)。
So etwas sehe ich hier nicht.
I don't see nothing like that here.
我在这里没有看到类似的东西。
Ja, aber ich...
Yeah, but I...
是啊，但是我…
Okay. Ich...
Okay. I...
好的。我…
Ich garantiere Ihnen Ihr Geld zurück.
I guarantee you your money back.
我保证退款给你。
Ich rede nicht von deinem verdammten Wort, Jerry.
I'm not talking about your damn word, Jerry.
我不是在谈论你那该死的话语，杰瑞。
Herrgott! Was zum Teufel machst du...
Jeez!
What the heck are you...
天哪！你到底在干什么……
Wir sind keine Bank, Jerry.
We're not a bank, Jerry.
我们不是银行，杰瑞。
Nun, schau. Ich möchte dich nicht aus der Schleife nehmen,
Well, look.
I don't want to cut you out of the loop,
好吧，听着。我不想让你失去了解情况的机会，
aber das hier ist ein gutes Geschäft. but this here's a good deal.
但这是一个很好的交易。
Ich nehme an, wenn Sie nicht interessiert sind,
I assume, if you're not interested,
我想，如果你不感兴趣，
Sie werden nichts dagegen haben, wenn wir unabhängig weitermachen. you won't mind if we move on it independenfly.
如果我们独立行动，你不会介意的。
Verdammt!
Damn it!
该死的！
Sie?
Hon?
她？
Ich habe die Lebensmittel besorgt!
I got the groceries!
我买到食品杂货了！
Ja, Wade, hallo. Hier ist Jerry. Ich...
Yeah, Wade, hi.
It's Jerry. I...
是的，韦德，你好。我是杰瑞。我……
Wade, hier ist Jerry. Ich weiß nicht, was ich tun soll. Hier ist Jean.
Wade, it's Jerry.
I don't know what to do.
It's Jean.
韦德，我是杰瑞。我不知道该怎么办。我是琼。
Ich weiß nicht, was ich tun soll. Es ist meine Frau.
I don't know what to do.
It's my wife.
我不知道该怎么办。这是我的妻子。
Ich weiß nicht, was ich tun soll. Es ist Jean.
I don't know what to do.
It's Jean.
我不知道该怎么办。这是 Jean。
Ja, Wade, ich... Ich bin's, Jerry. Ich...
Yeah, Wade, I...
It's Jerry. I...
是的，韦德，我……我是杰瑞。我……
Wade, hier ist Jerry. Ich... wir müssen reden.
Wade, it's Jerry.
I... We gotta talk.
韦德，我是杰瑞。我……我们得谈谈。
Es ist etwas... Herrgott, es ist furchtbar.
It's something...
Jeez. It's terrible.
这有点……天哪。太糟糕了。
Ja, Wade Gustafson, bitte.
Yeah, Wade Gustafson, please.
是的，请韦德·古斯塔夫森 (Wade Gustafson) 发言。
Halt die Klappe,
Shut the fuck up,
闭嘴，
oder ich werfe dich zurück in den Kofferraum, weißt du. or I'll throw you back into the trunk, you know.
不然我就把你扔回后备箱，你知道吗。
Jesus, das ist mehr, als ich Sie die ganze Woche sagen gehört habe.
Jesus, that's more than
I've heard you say all week.
天啊，这比我整个星期听到你说的话还多。
Scheiße.
Shit.
拉屎。
Oh, die Etiketten.
Oh, the tags.
哦，标签。
Alles klar, es sind nur die Tags.
All right, it's just the tags.
好的，这只是标签。
Ich habe meine Kennzeichen nie am Auto angebracht.
I never put my tags on the car.
我从来没有把我的标签贴在车上。
Alles klar, keine Sorge. Ich kümmere mich darum.
All right, don't worry.
I'll take care of this.
好吧，别担心。我会处理好这件事的。
Also gut, seien Sie ruhig da hinten, Lady,
All right, just keep it still back there, lady,
好的，女士，就让它在那里别动，
oder wir müssen Sie erschießen. or else we're gonna have to, you know, to shoot you.
否则我们就得开枪打死你。
Hey, ich kümmere mich darum.
Hey, I'll take care of this.
嘿，我会处理这件事的。
Wie kann ich Ihnen helfen, Officer?
How can I help you, Officer?
警官，我能为您做些什么？
Das ist also ein neues Auto, Sir?
This is a new car, then, sir?
那么，先生，这是一辆新车吗？
Das ist es sicherlich, Officer. Ich rieche immer noch.
It certainly is, Officer.
Still got that smell.
确实是，警官。还有那股味道。
Sie müssen temporäre Tags anzeigen,
You're required to display temporary tags,
您需要显示临时标签，
entweder im Kennzeichenbereich oder auf die Innenseite der Heckscheibe geklebt. either in the plate area or taped to the inside of the back window.
要么在车牌区域，要么用胶带贴在后窗内侧。
Sicherlich.
Certainly.
当然。
Kann ich bitte Ihren Führerschein und Ihre Zulassung sehen?
Can I see your license and registration, please?
我可以看一下您的驾照和登记证吗？
Sicherlich.
Certainly.
当然。
Ja, ich wollte das mit Klebeband befestigen ... das Etikett.
Yeah, I was gonna tape up those...
The tag.
是的，我要用胶带把那些...标签粘起来。
Wissen Sie, um die Vorschriften vollständig einzuhalten, muss es …
You know, to be in full compliance, but it must have...
你知道，要完全遵守，但必须......
Es muss mir entfallen sein.
It must have slipped my mind.
我肯定忘记了。
Das Beste wäre also vielleicht,
So maybe the best thing to do would be
所以也许最好的办法是
sich hier in Brainerd darum zu kümmern. to take care of that right here in Brainerd.
在布雷纳德处理此事。
Was ist das, Sir?
What's this, sir?
先生，这是什么？
Mein Führerschein und meine Zulassung.
My license and registration.
我的执照和登记。
Ja, ich möchte die Vorschriften einhalten.
Yeah, I want to be in compliance.
是的，我想遵守规定。
Ich dachte nur, wir könnten uns gleich hier darum kümmern,
I was just thinking we could take care of it right here,
我只是觉得我们可以在这里处理这件事，
in Brainerd. in Brainerd.
在布雷纳德。
Steck das bitte wieder in deine Tasche,
Put that back in your pocket, please,
请把它放回你的口袋里，
und steigen Sie bitte aus dem Auto aus, Sir. and step out of the car, please, sir.
先生，请下车。
Halt die Klappe.
Shut the fuck up.
闭嘴吧。
Boah.
Whoa.
哇哦。
Boah, Papa.
Whoa, daddy.
哇哦，爸爸。
Du wirst dich darum kümmern.
You'll take care of it.
你会处理好这件事的。
Du bist glatt, glatt, weißt du?
You are smooth, smooth, you know?
你很顺利，很顺利，你知道吗？
Oh, Papa.
Oh, daddy.
噢，爸爸。
Räumen Sie ihn einfach von der Straße.
Just clear him off the road.
只要把他从路上弄走就行了。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
NEIN!
No!
不！
Oh, Herrgott.
Oh, jeez.
噢，天哪。
Hallo. Hier ist Marge.
Hi. It's Marge.
嗨，我是玛吉。
Oh je. Wo?
Oh, my. Where?
噢，天哪。在哪儿？
Ja?
Yeah?
是的？
Oh, Herrgott.
Oh, jeez.
噢，天哪。
Okay. Im Handumdrehen da.
Okay. There in a jiff.
好的。一会儿就到了。
Also wirklich gut.
Real good, then.
那么，真的很好。
Du kannst schlafen. Es ist noch früh.
You can sleep.
It's early yet.
你可以睡觉了，还早。
Musst du gehen?
Got to go?
一定要走嗎？
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Ich mache dir ein paar Eier.
I'll fix you some eggs.
我去给你做些鸡蛋。
Es ist okay, Schatz. Ich muss los.
It's okay, hon.
I gotta run.
没关系，亲爱的。我得走了。
Du musst frühstücken, Marge.
You got to eat a breakfast, Marge.
你得吃早餐，玛吉。
Ich mache dir ein paar Eier.
I'll fix you some eggs.
我去给你做些鸡蛋。
Schatz, du kannst schlafen.
Hon, you can sleep.
亲爱的，你可以睡觉了。
Du musst frühstücken.
You gotta eat a breakfast.
你得吃早餐。
Ich mache dir ein paar Eier.
I'll fix you some eggs.
我去给你做些鸡蛋。
Norm.
规范。
Danke, Schatz. Zeit, aufzubrechen.
Thanks, hon.
Time to shove off.
谢谢，亲爱的。该出发了。
Ich liebe dich, Margie.
Love you, Margie.
爱你，玛吉。
Ich liebe dich, Schatz.
Love you, hon.
爱你，亲爱的。
Sie?
Hon?
她？
Ja?
Yeah?
是的？
Prowler braucht einen Sprung.
Prowler needs a jump.
徘徊者需要跳跃。
Hallo, Lou.
Hiya, Lou.
你好，卢。
Was hast du da?
What you got there?
你得到了什么？
Margie, ich dachte, du könntest ein kleines Aufwärmtraining gebrauchen.
Margie, thought you might need a little warm-up.
玛吉，我想你可能需要一点热身。
Vielen Dank.
Thanks a bunch.
非常感谢。
Also, was ist jetzt los?
So what's the deal now?
那么现在的情况怎么样？
Gary sagt, dreifacher Mord?
Gary says triple homicide?
加里说是三重谋杀？
Ja, sieht ziemlich schlimm aus.
Yeah, looks pretty bad.
是的，看上去很糟糕。
Zwei davon sind hier.
Two of them are over here.
其中两个在这儿。
Wo sind alle?
Where is everybody?
大家都在哪儿？
Nun, es ist kalt, Margie.
Well, it's cold, Margie.
嗯，天气很冷，玛吉。
Pass auf, wo du hintrittst, Margie.
Watch your step, Margie.
小心脚下，玛吉。
Herrgott, das bin ich.
Jeez.Sou.
天哪，我确实如此。
Herrgott!
Jeez!
天哪！
Hier ist der Zweite!
Here's the second one!
这是第二个！
Es ist im Kopf und in der Hand.
It's in the head and the hand there.
它在头和手那里。
Ich schätze, das ist eine Abwehrverletzung.
I guess that's a defensive wound.
我猜那是防御性伤口。
Oh ja?
Oh, yeah?
哦，是吗？
Wo ist der State Trooper?
Where's the state trooper?
州警在哪儿？
Da hinten ein gutes Stück, im Graben neben seinem Prowler.
Back there a good piece, in the ditch next to his prowler.
那儿有一块好东西，就在他巡逻车旁边的沟里。
Okay.
好的。
Also, ein Polizist hält jemanden an.
So we got a trooper pulls someone over.
所以我们派一名士兵把一个人拦了下来。
Wir haben eine Schießerei.
We got a shooting.
我们遭遇了枪击。
Diese Leute fahren vorbei.
These folks drive by.
这些人开车经过。
Es gibt eine Hochgeschwindigkeitsverfolgung. Endet hier.
There's a high-speed pursuit. ends here.
这是一场高速追逐。到此结束。
Und dann dieser Vollstreckungsdeal.
And then this execution-type deal.
然后是这种执行型交易。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Es würde mich sehr überraschen, wenn unser Verdächtiger aus Brainerd käme.
I'd be very surprised if our suspect was from Brainerd.
如果我们的嫌疑人来自布雷纳德，我会感到非常惊讶。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Und ich sage Ihnen was.
And I'll tell you what.
我会告诉你什么。
Seinem Fußabdruck nach sieht er aus wie ein großer Kerl.
From his footprint, he looks like a big fella.
从他的足迹来看，他看上去像是一个大个子。
Sehen Sie da unten etwas, Chef?
You see something down there, Chief?
酋长，你看到下面有什么东西吗？
Nein, ich glaube, ich muss kotzen.
No. I just think
I'm gonna barf.
不，我只是想吐。
Herrgott.
Jeez.
天哪。
Alles in Ordnung, Margie?
You okay, Margie?
你还好吗，玛吉？
Ja, mir geht es gut.
Yeah. I'm fine.
是的，我很好。
Es ist nur Morgenübelkeit.
It's just morning sickness.
这只是晨吐。
Nun, das ist vorbei.
Well, that passed.
嗯，那已经过去了。
Ja?
Yeah?
是的？
Ja. Jetzt habe ich wieder Hunger.
Yeah. Now
I'm hungry again.
是啊。现在我又饿了。
Hast du schon gefrühstückt, Margie?
You have breakfast yet, Margie?
你吃早饭了吗，玛吉？
Oh ja.
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
Norm hat ein paar Eier gemacht.
Norm made some eggs.
诺姆做了一些鸡蛋。
Ja?
Yeah?
是的？
Also...
Well...
出色地...
Was nun, meinen Sie?
What now, do you think?
那么您觉得现在怎么样？
Schauen wir uns den Soldaten an.
Let's go take a look at that trooper.
我们去看看那名士兵。
Hier gibt es verschiedene Fußabdrücke, Lou.
There's different footprints here, Lou.
这里有不同的足迹，卢。
Ja?
Yeah?
是的？
Ja. Der Typ ist kleiner als sein Kumpel.
Yeah. This guy's smaller than his buddy.
是啊。这家伙比他的朋友小。
Oh ja?
Oh, yeah?
哦，是吗？
Um Himmels Willen.
For Pete's sake.
看在上帝的份上。
Wie sieht es aus, Marge?
How's it look, Marge?
看起来怎么样，玛吉？
Nun, er hat seine Waffe an der Hüfte,
Well, he's got his gun on his hip there,
嗯，他的枪就挂在腰间，
und er sieht aus wie ein netter Kerl. and he looks like a nice enough guy.
他看上去是个不错的家伙。
Es ist wirklich schade.
It's a real shame.
真是可惜。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Sie haben da nicht an seinem Auto herumgepfuscht, oder?
Didn't monkey with his car there, did you?
你没有在那里捣乱他的车吧？
Auf keinen Fall.
No way.
决不。
Nun, jemand hat sein Licht ausgeschaltet.
Well, somebody shut his lights.
嗯，有人关掉了灯。
Ich schätze, der kleine Kerl saß da ​​drin
I guess the little guy sat in there
我猜那个小家伙坐在那里
wartete auf die Rückkehr seines Kumpels. waiting for his buddy to come back.
等待他的朋友回来。
Ja, hier draußen wäre es kalt gewesen.
Yeah, it would have been cold out here.
是的，这里肯定很冷。
Na klar. Meinst du, Dave hat schon geöffnet?
Heck, yeah.
You think is Dave open yet?
哎呀，是的。你认为 Dave 已经开业了吗？
Dave?
戴夫？
Sie glauben nicht, dass er in etwas verwickelt ist...
You don't think he's mixed up in...
你不认为他参与了......
Oh nein, nein. Ich möchte Norm nur ein paar Tauwürmer besorgen.
Oh, no, no. I just want to get Norm some night crawlers.
哦，不，不。我只是想给诺姆买些夜蚯蚓。
Haben Sie in seinem Zitatbuch nachgesehen?
Did you look in his citation book?
你看过他的引文簿吗？
Ja. Das letzte Fahrzeug, das er angegeben hat, war ein hellbrauner Cierra um 2:18 Uhr.
Yeah. Last vehicle he wrote in was a tan Cierra at 2:18 am.
是的。他写的最后一辆车是一辆棕褐色的 Cierra，时间是凌晨 2:18。
Unter dem Kennzeichen schrieb er „DLR“.
Under plate number he put "DLR."
他在车牌号下填写了“DLR”。
Ich nehme an, sie haben ihn aufgehalten oder erschossen
I figure they stopped him or shot him
我想他们拦住了他或者开枪打死了他
bevor er die Kennzeichennummer fertig ausfüllen konnte. before he could finish filling out the tag number.
他还来不及填写完标签号码。
Also habe ich den Staat dazu gebracht, nach einem Cierra zu suchen, dessen Kennzeichen mit „DLR“ beginnt.
So, I got the State looking for a Cierra with a tag starting "DLR."
因此，我让州政府寻找标签以“DLR”开头的 Cierra。
Sie haben noch kein Match.
They don't got no match yet.
他们还没有比赛。
Ich bin nicht sicher, ob ich dir 100% zustimme
I'm not sure that
I agree with you 100%
我不确定我是否 100% 同意你的观点
zu deiner Polizeiarbeit dort, Lou. on your police work there, Lou.
关于你在那里的警察工作，卢。
Ja ja.
Yeah?
Yeah.
是啊是啊。
Ich denke, das Fahrzeug dort hatte wahrscheinlich Händlerkennzeichen.
I think that vehicle there probably had dealer plates.
我认为那辆车可能有经销商牌照。
"DLR."
“DLR。”
Oh.
哦。
Herrgott.
Jeez.
天哪。
Sag, Lou,
Say, Lou,
卢，
hast du den über den Kerl gehört did you hear the one about the guy
你听说过那个关于那个家伙的故事吗
die sich keine personalisierten Nummernschilder leisten konnten, who couldn't afford personalized plates,
买不起个性化车牌的人，
Also hat er seinen Namen in J3L-2404 geändert?
So he went and changed his name to J3L-2404?
所以他就把名字改成了 J3L-2404？
Ja, das ist gut.
Yeah. That's a good one.
是的。这个很好。
Hören Sie, ich weiß nur: Wenn Sie ein Problem haben, rufen Sie einen Fachmann.
Look, all's I know is, you got a problem, you call a professional.
听着，我所知道的是，你遇到了问题，你就打电话给专业人士。
Nein. Sie sagten, keine Polizisten.
No. They said no cops.
没有。他们说没有警察。
Das haben sie verdammt deutlich gemacht, Wade.
They were darn clear on that, Wade.
韦德，他们对此非常清楚。
Sie sagten: „Rufen Sie die Polizei, und wir schießen …“
They said,
"You call your cops, and we're gonna shoot..."
他们说，“你打电话给警察，我们就要开枪了……”
Natürlich werden sie das sagen
Of course they're gonna say that
他们当然会这么说
Wo ist mein Schutz? Sie haben Jean hier.
Where's my protection?
They got Jean here.
我的保护措施在哪里？他们把 Jean 抓到这里了。
Wenn ich diesen Hurensöhnen eine Million Dollar gebe,
If I give these sons of bitches
$1 million,
如果我给这些混蛋一百万美元，
wo ist meine Garantie, dass sie sie gehen lassen? where's my guarantee they're gonna let her go?
我怎么能保证他们会放她走呢？
Nun, sie...
Well, they...
嗯，他们……
1 Million Dollar ist verdammt viel Geld.
$1 million is a lot of damn money.
100 万美元是一大笔钱。
Ja, aber... Da sind sie. Sie haben meine Tochter.
Yeah. but...
There they are.
They got my daughter.
是的。但是...他们就在那里。他们抓走了我的女儿。
Denken Sie darüber nach, Wade.
Think this thing through here, Wade.
仔细想想这件事，韦德。
Sie geben ihnen, was sie wollen, warum lassen sie sie nicht gehen?
You give them what they want, why won't they let her go?
你给了他们想要的东西，他们为什么不放她走？
In diesem Fall musst du mir zuhören, Wade.
You got to listen to me on this one, Wade.
这件事你得听我的，韦德。
Mist, das weißt du nicht.
Heck, you don't know.
哎呀，你不知道。
Du pfeifst hier einfach Dixie.
You're just whistling
Dixie here.
你只是在这儿吹着迪克西的口哨。
Ich sage, die Polizei kann uns diesbezüglich beraten.
I'm saying the cops, they can advise us on this.
我说警察可以就此事给我们提供建议。
Ich sage, rufen Sie einen Fachmann an.
I'm saying call a professional.
我是说打电话给专业人士。
Nein, keine Bullen.
No. No cops.
没有，没有警察。
Das ist endgültig. Das ist mein Deal, Wade.
That's final.
This is my deal here, Wade.
就这样吧。这是我的约定，韦德。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Jean ist hier meine Frau.
Jean is my wife here.
吉恩 (Jean) 是我的妻子。
Ich muss Ihnen sagen, Wade, ich neige hier zu Jerrys Standpunkt.
I gotta tell you, Wade,
I'm leaning to
Jerry's viewpoint here.
我得告诉你，韦德，我倾向于杰瑞的观点。
Also...
Well...
出色地...
Wir müssen Jean beschützen. Diese.“
We got to protect Jean.
These”.
我们必须保护 Jean。这些”。
Wir haben hier keine Karten in der Hand, Wade.
We're not holding any cards here, Wade.
我们这里没有任何底牌，韦德。
Sie haben sie alle. Sie haben also das Sagen.
They got them all.
So they call the shots.
他们得到了一切。所以他们说了算。
Du tust verdammt nochmal.
You're darn tooting.
你吹得真够呛。
Oh, verdammt.
Oh, damn it.
噢，该死。
Ich sage es dir.
I'm telling you.
我告诉你。
Also, warum machen wir nicht...
Well, why don't we...
嗯，我们为什么不...
Stan, ich denke, wir sollten ihnen eine halbe Million anbieten.
Stan, I'm thinking we should offer them a half a million.
斯坦，我想我们应该给他们五十万美元。
Und jetzt komm her!
Now, come on here!
现在，过来吧！
Auf keinen Fall, Wade. Auf keinen Fall.
No way, Wade.
No way.
没办法，韦德，没办法。
Wir machen hier keinen Kuhhandel, Wade.
We're not horse-trading here, Wade.
我们不是来这里讨价还价的，韦德。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Wir müssen die Zähne zusammenbeißen.
We gotta just bite the bullet on this thing.
我们必须咬紧牙关，完成这件事。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Also, was ist hier der nächste Schritt, Jerry?
So, well, what's the next step here, Jerry?
那么，杰瑞，下一步该怎么做呢？
Sie werden mich anrufen und mir Anweisungen für einen Abwurf geben.
They're gonna call me up and give me instructions for a drop.
他们会打电话给我并告诉我投放的具体说明。
Ich soll das Geld morgen bereit haben.
I'm supposed to have the money ready tomorrow.
我应该明天就准备好钱。
Verdammt!
Damn it!
该死的！
Wie war alles heute?
How was everything today?
今天过得怎么样？
Ja. Jetzt richtig gut.
Yeah. Real good, now.
是的。现在很好。
Wie geht's?
How you doing?
你好吗？
Okay. Jetzt besorgen wir das Geld.
Okay.
Now, we'll get the money together.
好的。现在我们要把钱凑齐。
Mach dir keine Sorgen, Jerry.
Don't worry about it, Jerry.
别担心，杰瑞。
Möchten Sie, dass jemand bei Ihnen zu Hause bleibt, bis der Anruf kommt?
Now, do you want anyone at home with you till they call?
现在，在他们打电话之前你想要有人在家陪你吗？
Nein, ich... Sie tun es nicht...
No. I...
They don't...
不，我…他们不…
Sie sollten sich lediglich um mich kümmern.
They were just supposed to be dealing with me.
他们只是应该来处理我的事情。
Sie waren wirklich klar. Ja.
They were real clear.
Yeah.
他们说得很清楚。是的。
Wissen Sie, sie sagten, niemand würde zuhören.
You know, they said no one listening in.
你知道，他们说没人在听。
Sie werden zuschauen.
They'll be watching.
他们将会观看。
Weißt du, vielleicht ist das alles Blödsinn,
You know, maybe it's all bull,
你知道，也许这都是胡说八道，
aber wie du gesagt hast, Stan, sie haben das Sagen. but like you said, Stan, they're calling the shots.
但就像你说的，斯坦，他们在发号施令。
Okay.
好的。
Wird es Scotty jetzt gut gehen?
Now, is Scotty gonna be all right?
那么斯科蒂还好吗？
Ja. Herrgott. Scotty.
Yeah. Jeez. Scotty.
是啊。天哪。斯科蒂。
Ja. Ich werde mit ihm reden.
Yeah. I'll go talk to him.
是的。我会去和他谈谈。
Wie geht es dir, Scotty?
How you doing there, Scotty?
你好吗，斯科蒂？
Papa...
Dad...
爸爸...
Was machen Sie?
What are they doing?
他们在做什么？
Was denkst du, machen sie mit Mama?
What do you think they're doing with Mom?
你认为他们和妈妈在做什么？
Es ist okay, Scotty.
It's okay, Scotty.
没关系，斯科蒂。
Sie werden ihr nicht wehtun wollen.
They're not gonna wanna hurt her any.
他们不会想伤害她。
Diese Männer wollen nur Geld.
These men, they just want money.
这些人，他们只想要钱。
Ja, also, was ist, wenn etwas schief geht, Dad?
Yeah, well, what if something goes wrong, Dad?
是啊，但是，如果出了什么问题怎么办呢，爸爸？
Nein, nein. Hier läuft nichts schief.
No, no.
Nothing's going wrong here.
不，不。这里没什么事。
Großvater und ich sorgen dafür, dass das richtig gehandhabt wird.
Granddad and I, we're, we're making sure this gets handled right.
爷爷和我，我们正在确保这件事得到妥善处理。
Ich denke wirklich, wir sollten hier die Polizei rufen.
I really think we should call the cops here.
我真的认为我们应该报警。
Nein, nein. Niemand darf von dieser Sache wissen.
No. No. No one can know about this thing.
不，不，没有人可以知道这件事。
Wir müssen mit diesen Jungs Ball spielen.
We gotta play ball with these guys.
我们必须和这些人一起比赛。
Fragen Sie Stan Grossman, er wird Ihnen dasselbe sagen.
You ask Stan Grossman, he'll tell you the same thing.
如果你问斯坦·格罗斯曼，他也会告诉你同样的事情。
Ja. Aber, Papa...
Yeah. But, Dad...
是啊。但是，爸爸……
Wir werden Mama für dich zurückholen, aber wir müssen mitspielen.
We're gonna get
Mom back for you, but we gotta play ball.
我们会把妈妈带回来给你，但是我们必须合作。
Du weisst?
You know?
你知道？
Das ist hier der Deal.
That's the deal here.
这就是事情的经过。
Wenn Lorraine oder Sylvia anruft,
So if Lorraine calls, or Sylvia,
所以如果洛林或者西尔维娅打电话来，
Sie sagen einfach, dass Mama mit Pearl und Marty unten in Florida ist. you just say
Mom's down in Florida, with Pearl and Marty.
你只需说妈妈在佛罗里达，和 Pearl 和 Marty 在一起。
Das ist das Beste, was wir hier tun können.
That's the best we can do here.
这是我们能做的最好的事情了。
NEIN!
No!
不！
NEIN!
No!
不！
Oh Gott.
Oh, God.
哦，天啊。
Mittagszeit.
Lunchtime.
午餐时间。
Danke, Margaret.
Thanks,
Margaret.
谢谢，玛格丽特。
Hallo. Hey.
Hi. Hey.
嗨，嘿。
Willy. Carol.
威利。卡罗尔。
Janie, bitte noch zwei von diesen Skin 80 Soft.
Janie, two more of those
Skin 80 Soft, please.
珍妮，请再来两瓶 Skin 80 Soft 乳液。
Sicher.
Sure thing.
当然可以。
Er, Schatz.
Hiya, hon.
他，亲爱的。
Ich habe dir etwas zu Mittag mitgebracht, Margie.
I brought you some lunch, Margie.
我给你带了些午餐，玛吉。
Was sind das? Nachtkriecher?
What are those?
Night crawlers?
那些是什么？夜蚯蚓？
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Oh, danke, Schatz.
Oh, thanks, hon.
噢，谢谢，亲爱的。
Aber sicher. Danke fürs Mittagessen.
You bet.
Thanks for lunch.
当然。谢谢你的午餐。
Ja. Sieht ziemlich gut aus.
Yeah.
Looks pretty good.
是的。看上去很不错。
Was haben wir hier, Amys?
What do we got here, Amy's?
我们在这里得到了什么，艾米？
Wie läuft es mit dem Malen?
How's the painting going?
绘画进行得怎样？
Ziemlich gut.
Pretty good.
不错。
Habe herausgefunden, dass die Hautmans dieses Jahr ein Gemälde einreichen.
Found out the Hautmans are entering a painting this year.
发现 Hautmans 今年要参加一场绘画创作。
Schatz, du bist besser als sie.
Hon, you're better than them.
亲爱的，你比他们更好。
Sie sind wirklich gut.
They're real good.
他们真的很棒。
Sie sind gut, Norm, aber du bist besser als sie.
They're good, Norm, but you're better than them.
他们很优秀，诺姆，但你比他们更好。
Meinen Sie das?
You think so?
你这么认为吗？
Hey, du hast mir Arby's auf den Hals gehetzt.
Hey, you got Arby's all over me.
嘿，你把我全都弄到 Arby 了。
Hallo, Norm. Wie läuft es mit dem Malen?
Hiya, Norm.
How's the painting going?
嗨，Norm。绘画进行得怎么样了？
Nicht so schlecht. Weißt du.
Not too bad.
You know.
还不错。你知道的。
Wie läuft es mit dem Fahrzeug?
How we doing on that vehicle?
我们在那辆车上怎么样？
Nun, letzte Nacht hat kein Motel eine tan Cierra registriert,
Well, no motels registered any tan Cierra last night,
嗯，昨晚没有一家汽车旅馆登记任何棕褐色的 Cierra，
Aber am Abend zuvor checkten zwei Männer im Blue Ox ein, but the night before, two men checked into the Blue Ox,
但前一天晚上，两名男子入住了蓝牛酒店，
Registrieren Sie eine Cierra und lassen Sie das Tag-Feld leer. registering a Cierra and leaving the tag space blank.
注册 Cierra 并将标签空间留空。
Herrgott, das ist ein guter Hinweis.
Jeez, that's a good lead.
哎呀，这是一个很好的线索。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Blue Ox, das ist die Trucker-Bude da draußen auf der I-35?
Blue Ox, that's that truckers' joint out there on I-35?
Blue Ox，那是 35 号州际公路旁的卡车司机店吗？
Ja. Der Besitzer saß damals am Schreibtisch.
Yeah. Owner was on the desk then.
是的。当时老板就在办公桌上。
Sagte, die beiden hätten Besuch.
Said these two had company.
说这两个人有同伴。
Oh ja?
Oh, yeah?
哦，是吗？
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Ja, das haben wir beide. Sie ist auch aufs College gegangen.
Yeah, we both did.
She went to college, too.
是的，我们都读过大学。她也读过大学。
Ich war ungefähr anderthalb Jahre in Normandale.
I went to
Normandale for about a year and a half.
我去诺曼代尔大约一年半。
Ja, dort haben wir uns kennengelernt.
Yeah, that's where we met.
是的，我们就在那里见面的。
Aber ich habe es trotzdem abgebrochen.
But I dropped out, though.
但我还是退学了。
Ja. Sie ist gefallen.
Yeah.
She dropped.
是的。她掉了下来。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Also, woher kommt ihr, Mädels?
So where you girls from?
那么你们来自哪里？
Chaska. Der Schweiß.
Chaska.
Le Sueur.
查斯卡。汗水。
Aber ich bin in White Bear Lake zur High School gegangen.
But I went to high school in White Bear Lake.
但我在白熊湖上的高中。
Auf geht's, Bears.
Go Bears.
加油，熊队。
Okay. Ich möchte, dass Sie mir sagen, wie diese Kerle aussahen.
Okay. I want you to tell me what these fellows looked like.
好的。我想让你告诉我这些家伙长什么样子。
Also, der kleine Kerl sah irgendwie komisch aus.
Well, the little guy, he was kind of funny-looking.
嗯，这个小家伙，看上去有点滑稽。
Inwiefern?
In what way?
以什么方式？
Ich weiß nicht. Sieht einfach komisch aus.
I don't know.
Just funny-looking.
我不知道。只是看上去很有趣。
Können Sie das genauer sagen?
Can you be any more specific?
你能更具体一点吗？
Das kann ich nicht wirklich sagen.
I couldn't really say.
我真说不上来。
Er war nicht beschnitten.
He wasn't circumcised.
他未受过割礼。
Sah er abgesehen davon komisch aus?
Was he funny-looking apart from that?
除此以外他看起来还有什么滑稽的吗？
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Sie hatten also Sex mit dem kleinen Kerl.
So, you were having sex with the little fella, then.
那么，你当时正在和那个小家伙发生性关系。
Mh-hm.
Uh-huh.
嗯嗯。
Können Sie mir sonst noch etwas über ihn erzählen?
Is there anything else you can tell me about him?
您还能告诉我一些关于他的事情吗？
Nein. Wie ich schon sagte, er sah komisch aus.
No. Like I say, he was funny-looking.
不。正如我所说，他看上去很有趣。
Sogar mehr als die meisten Menschen.
More than most people, even.
甚至比大多数人还要多。
Was ist mit dem anderen Kerl?
What about the other fella?
那另外一个人怎么样了？
Er war etwas älter.
He was a little older.
他年纪稍大一些。
Wissen Sie, er sah aus wie der Marlboro-Mann.
You know, he looked like the Marlboro Man.
你知道，他看上去就像万宝路男人。
Oh, ja? Ja.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
哦，是吗？是的。
Aber vielleicht sage ich, dass, wissen Sie,
But maybe I'm saying that, you know,
但也许我想说的是，
weil er viele Marlboros geraucht hat.
'cause he smoked a lot of Marlboros.
因为他抽了很多万宝路。
Wissen Sie, so etwas Unterbewusstes.
You know, like a subconscious type of thing.
你知道，就像一种潜意识的东西。
Oh ja, das kann passieren.
Oh, yeah, that can happen.
噢，是的，那是有可能发生的。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Hey, sie sagten, sie würden in die Twin Cities fahren.
Hey, they said they were going to the Twin Cities.
嘿，他们说他们要去双城。
Oh, ja? Ja!
Oh. yeah?
Yeah!
噢。是吗？是的！
Ja, ist das für Sie nützlich?
Yeah, is that useful to you?
是啊，这对你有用吗？
Darauf kannst du wetten. Ja.
You betcha. Yeah.
没错。是的。
Ja ja.
Yeah
Yeah.
是啊是啊。
Aufleuchten!
Come on!
快点！
Verdammt!
Goddamn it!
该死！
Jesus Christus.
Jesus Christ.
耶稣基督。
Verdammte Scheißkiste.
Fucking shitbox.
他妈的垃圾桶。
Bin seit Tagen hier.
Been here for days.
我已经在这里好几天了。
Verdammt. Nichts zu tun.
Damn it.
Nothing to do.
可恶，没事可做。
Das verdammte Fernsehen macht nicht mal...
Fucking TV doesn't even...
他妈的电视甚至没有......
Verdammt, komm schon! Stöber mich rein, Mann. Gib mir ein verdammtes Signal.
Damn it, come on!
Plug me in, man.
Give me a fucking signal.
该死，快点！快给我插上电源，哥们。给我一个信号。
Verdammt!
Goddamn it!
该死！
Unglaublich! Komm schon!
Unbelievable! Come on!
难以置信！加油！
Gott...
God...
上帝...
Scheiße!
Fuck!
他妈的！
Komm, schließ mich an das Ozon an, Baby! Komm schon!
Come on, plug me into the ozone, baby! Come on!
来吧，把我插进臭氧层吧，宝贝！来吧！
Aufleuchten!
Come on!
快点！
Scheiße! Scheiße!
Fuck! Fuck!
操！操！
Scheiße! Scheiße!
Fuck! Fuck!
操！操！
Der Borkenkäfer trägt den Wurm in sein Nest
The bark beetle carries the worm to its nest
树皮甲虫把虫子带回巢穴
Dort füttert es seine Jungen bis zu sechs Monate lang. where it will feed its young for up to six months.
它会在那里喂养幼崽长达六个月。
Im Frühjahr schlüpfen die Larven und der Zyklus beginnt von neuem.
In the spring, the larvae hatch, and the cycle begins again.
春天，幼虫孵化，循环又重新开始。
Also...
Well...
出色地...
Ich gehe schlafen, Norm.
I'm turning in, Norm.
我要睡觉了，诺姆。
Oh ja?
Oh, yeah?
哦，是吗？
Hier wirft es die Larvenhülle ab.
Here it is, throwing off the larval envelope.
它就在这里，正在剥去幼虫的外壳。
Hallo?
Hello?
你好？
Ja. Ist das Marge?
Yeah.
Is this Marge?
是啊。这是玛吉吗？
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Margie Olmstead?
玛吉·奥姆斯特德？
Ja. Wer ist das?
Yeah. Who's this?
是啊。他是谁？
Das ist Mike Yanagita!
This is Mike Yanagita!
我是 Mike Yanagita！
Du weißt schon, Mike Yanagita. Erinnerst du dich an mich?
You know, Mike Yanagita.
Remember me?
你知道，麦克·柳田。还记得我吗？
Mike Yanagita?
麦克柳田？
Ja!
Yeah!
是的！
Nun ja!
Well, yeah!
嗯，是的！
Natürlich erinnere ich mich an dich.
Course I remember you.
我当然记得你。
Wie geht es dir? Wie spät ist es?
How are you doing?
What time is it?
你好嗎？现在几点了？
Oh Mann, es ist 10:45 Uhr.
Oh, jeez.
It's 10:45.
哦，天哪。现在是 10:45。
Ich hoffe, ich habe dich nicht geweckt.
I hope
I didn't wake you.
我希望我没有吵醒你。
Nein, das ist okay.
No. That's okay.
不，没关系。
Ja, ich bin unten in den Twin Cities,
Yeah, I'm down in the Twin Cities,
是的，我在双城，
und ich habe gerade im Fernsehen die Schießereien in Brainerd gesehen. and I was just watching on TV about these shootings up in Brainerd.
我刚刚在电视上看到了布雷纳德发生的枪击事件。
Und ich habe Sie dort in den Nachrichten gesehen.
And I saw you on the news there.
我在那里的新闻上看到了你。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Ich dachte: „Meine Güte, ist das Margie Olmstead?“
I thought,
"Jeez, is that
Margie Olmstead?"
我心想：“天哪，那是玛吉·奥姆斯特德吗？”
Ich kann es nicht glauben.
I can't believe it.
我简直不敢相信。
Ja, das bin ich.
Yeah, that's me.
是的，那就是我。
Also, wie zum Teufel geht es dir?
Well, how the heck are you?
那么，你到底怎么样了？
Okay. Du weißt schon.
Okay. You know.
好的。你知道的。
Okay.
好的。
Ja ja.
Yeah?
Yeah.
是啊是啊。
Wie geht's?
How you doing?
你好吗？
Ziemlich gut.
Pretty good.
不错。
Na ja, zum Teufel.
Well, heck.
好吧，哎呀。
Es ist so lange her, Mike.
It's been such a longtime, Mike.
已经过去好久了，迈克。
Es ist toll, von Ihnen zu hören.
It's great to hear from you.
很高兴收到您的来信。
Ja, du hast dein...
Yeah, you got your...
是的，你得到了你的...
Dies wird hier geladen. Dies hat Ihre unabhängige...
This is loaded here.
This has your independent...
这是在这里加载的。这有你的独立...
Ihr Frontantrieb, Zahnstangenlenkung,
Your front-wheel drive, rack-and-pinion steering,
你的前轮驱动，齿条齿轮转向，
Antiblockiersystem, Alarmanlage, Radar, antilock brakes, alarm, radar,
防抱死制动系统、警报器、雷达、
und ich kann es Ihnen mit einem tollen Dichtungsmittel geben. and I can give it to you with a heck of a sealant.
我可以给你一个非常好的密封剂。
Dieses TruCoat-Zeug hält das Salz fern.
This TruCoat stuff, it'll keep the salt off.
这种 TruCoat 材料可以防止盐分进入。
Ja, ich brauche allerdings kein Dichtungsmittel.
Yeah, I don't need no sealant, though.
是的，但我不需要密封剂。
Ja. Das brauchst du nicht.
Yeah.
You don't need that.
是的。你不需要这个。
Haben Sie hier an eine Finanzierung gedacht?
Now, were you thinking of financing here?
现在，您是否考虑在这里融资？
Sie sollten sich dieses aktuellen GMAC-Plans bewusst sein.
You ought to be aware of this GMAC plan they have now.
您应该了解他们现在的 GMAC 计划。
Es ist wirklich super.
It's really super.
真是太棒了。
Ich habe einen Anruf für dich, Jerry.
Got a call for you, Jerry.
有你的电话，杰瑞。
Ja, okay.
Yeah, okay.
嗯，好的。
Jerry Lundegaard.
杰瑞·伦德加德。
Alles klar, Jerry, hast du das Telefon für dich allein?
All right, Jerry, you got the phone to yourself?
好的，杰瑞，你一个人打电话吗？
Nun ja.
Well, yeah.
嗯，是的。
Wissen Sie, wer das ist?
You know who this is?
你知道这是谁吗？
Nun ja, ich habe eine Idee.
Well, yeah,
I got an idea.
嗯，是的，我有一个主意。
Wie läuft es mit Cierra für Sie?
How's that Cierra working out for you?
Cierra 对你来说怎么样？
Die Umstände haben sich geändert, Jerry.
Circumstances have changed, Jerry.
情况已经变了，杰瑞。
Also...
Well...
出色地...
Wie meinst du das?
What do you mean?
你是什​​么意思？
Die Dinge haben sich geändert. Die Umstände, Jerry, sind nicht auf höhere Gewalt zurückzuführen.
Things have changed.
Circumstances, Jerry, beyond the acts of God.
事情已经变了。杰瑞，情况已经超出了上帝的旨意。
Höhere Gewalt.
Force majeure.
不可抗力。
Was zum...
What the...
啥...
Wie geht es Jean?
How's Jean?
吉恩怎么样了？
Wer ist Jean?
Who's Jean?
谁是吉恩？
Meine Frau. Was zum...
My wife. What the...
我的老婆。怎么了……
Ihr geht es gut, aber in Brainerd sind drei Leute
She's all right, but there's three people up in Brainerd
她没事，但布雷纳德有三个人
denen es nicht so gut geht, das kann ich Ihnen sagen. who aren't so okay,
I'll tell you that.
谁不是那么好，我会告诉你的。
Wovon zum Teufel redest du?
What the heck are you talking about?
你到底在说什么？
Lassen Sie uns diesen Deal hier oben einfach abschließen.
Let's just finish this deal up here.
我们就就此结束这笔交易吧。
Es ist Blut vergossen worden, Jerry.
Blood has been shed, Jerry.
血已经流了，杰瑞。
Was zum Teufel meinst du?
What the heck do you mean?
你到底是什么意思？
Drei Personen in Brainerd.
Three people in Brainerd.
布雷纳德的三个人。
Oh, Herrgott.
Oh, jeez.
噢，天哪。
Das stimmt, und wir brauchen mehr Geld.
That's right, and we need more money.
没错，我们需要更多的钱。
Wovon zum Teufel redest du?
What the heck are you talking about?
你到底在说什么？
In was habt ihr euch da hineinmanövriert, Jungs?
What do you fellas got yourself mixed up in?
你们这些家伙到底参与到什么事情中去了？
Wir brauchen mehr Geld...
We need more money...
我们需要更多的钱……
Es sollte eigentlich eine unkomplizierte Sache werden.
This was supposed to be a no-rough-stuff type deal.
这本该是一笔不带粗暴的交易。
Unterbrich mich nie, Jerry! Halt einfach die Klappe!
Don't ever interrupt me, Jerry!
Just shut the fuck up!
别打断我，杰瑞！闭上你的臭嘴！
Es tut mir leid, aber ich, ich ...
Well, I'm sorry, but I just, I...
嗯，很抱歉，但是我只是，我......
Ich werde nicht mit dir diskutieren, Jerry. Ich werde nicht diskutieren!
I'm not gonna debate you, Jerry.
I'm not gonna debate!
我不会跟你辩论，杰瑞。我不会跟你辩论！
Wir wollen jetzt die gesamten 80.000.
We now want the entire 80,000.
我们现在想要全部8万人。
Oh, um Himmels willen.
Oh, for Christ's sake here.
噢，看在基督的份上。
Es ist Blut vergossen worden.
Blood has been shed.
血已经流了。
Wir sind ein Risiko eingegangen, Jerry.
We've incurred risk, Jerry.
我们已经承担了风险，杰瑞。
Ich komme morgen in die Stadt.
I'm coming into town tomorrow.
我明天要进城。
Sie haben das Geld bereit.
You have the money ready.
你已经准备好钱了。
Wir hatten hier eine Abmachung. Eine Abmachung ist eine Abmachung.
Now, we had a deal here.
A deal's a deal.
现在，我们达成了协议。协议就是协议。
Ist es das, Jerry?
Is it, Jerry?
是吗，杰瑞？
Fragen Sie diese drei armen Seelen da oben in Brainerd, ob ein Deal ein Deal ist.
You ask those three poor souls up in Brainerd if a deal's a deal.
你去问布雷纳德那三个可怜的家伙，这笔交易算不算是交易。
Nur zu, fragen Sie sie!
Go ahead, ask them!
来吧，问他们！
Was zum Teufel meinst du?
The heck do you mean?
你到底是什么意思？
„Was zum Teufel meinst du?“ Wir sehen uns morgen.
"The heck do you mean?"
I'll see you tomorrow.
“你到底是什么意思？”明天见。
Ja?
Yeah?
是的？
Jérôme Lundegaard?
Jerome Lundegaard?
杰罗姆·伦德加德？
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Das ist Reilly Diefenbach von GMAC.
This is Reilly Diefenbach at GMAC.
我是 GMAC 的 Reilly Diefenbach。
Sir, ich habe die versprochenen Fahrzeug-IDs nicht erhalten.
Sir, I've not received those vehicle IDs you promised.
先生，我还没有收到您承诺的车辆身份证。
Ja. Ich...
Yeah. I...
是啊。我……
Die sind in der Post.
Those are in the mail.
这些都在邮件里。
Das kann durchaus sein. Ich muss Sie jedoch informieren,
That very well may be.
I must inform you, however,
很有可能。不过，我必须告诉你，
dass, wenn diese Zahlen nicht bis morgen Nachmittag eingehen, that absent the receipt of those numbers by tomorrow afternoon,
如果明天下午之前没有收到这些数字，
Ich werde diese Angelegenheit an unsere Rechtsabteilung weiterleiten müssen.
I will have to refer this matter to our legal department.
我必须将此事提交给我们的法律部门。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Meine Geduld ist am Ende. Ja.
My patience is at an end.
Yeah.
我的耐心已经到了极限。是的。
Guten Tag, Sir. Ja.
Good day, sir.
Yeah.
您好，先生。是的。
Hallo, Norm. Wie geht es dir, Margie?
Hi, Norm.
How you doing, Margie?
嗨，诺姆。你好吗，玛吉？
Wie ist das Frikassee?
How's the fricassee?
炖肉怎么样？
Ziemlich verdammt gut. Willst du etwas?
Pretty darn good.
You want some?
相当不错。你想要一些吗？
Oh nein. Ich habe …
Oh, no. I got...
噢，不。我得……
Hey, Norm, ich dachte, du würdest oben in Mille Lacs Eisfischen gehen.
Hey, Norm, I thought you was going ice fishing up at Mille Lacs.
嘿，诺姆，我以为你要去米尔拉克斯冰钓。
Ja. Nach dem Mittagessen.
Yeah. After lunch.
是的。午饭后。
Was hast du da?
What you got there?
你得到了什么？
Die Zahlen, nach denen Sie gefragt haben.
The numbers you asked for.
您要求的数字。
Anrufe vom Münztelefon in der Lobby des Blue Ox.
Calls made from the lobby pay phone at the Blue Ox.
从 Blue Ox 大堂付费电话拨打的电话。
Zwei nach Minneapolis in dieser Nacht.
Two to Minneapolis that night.
当晚有两人飞往明尼阿波利斯。
Das erste ist eine Spedition
First one's a trucking company
第一家是一家卡车运输公司
und das zweite ist ein Privathaus, and second one's a private residence,
第二处是私人住宅，
ein Shep Proudfoot. a Shep Proudfoot.
谢普·普劳德福特 (Shep Proudfoot)。
Ein Was?
A What?
什么？
Shep Proudfoot. Das ist ein Name.
Shep Proudfoot.
That's a name.
Shep Proudfoot。这是个名字。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Okay. Ja.
Okay. Yeah.
好的。是的。
Ich glaube, dann fahre ich mal dorthin.
Think I'll take a drive down there, then.
那么我想开车去那里。
Ach ja? Twin Cities.
Oh, yeah?
Twin Cities.
哦，是吗？双城。
Oh ja?
Oh, yeah?
哦，是吗？
Verdammt, ich möchte ein Teil dieser Sache sein.
Damn it, I want to be a part of this thing.
该死的，我想成为这件事的一部分。
Nein, Wade, sie waren wirklich eindeutig.
No. Wade, they were real clear.
不，韦德，他们真的很清楚。
Sie sagten, sie würden morgen mit Anweisungen anrufen,
They said they'd call tomorrow with instructions,
他们说他们明天会打电话告知具体指示，
und es muss von mir allein geliefert werden. and it's gotta be delivered by me alone.
而且必须由我一人去递送。
Es ist mein Geld, ich werde es liefern.
It's my money,
I'll deliver it.
这是我的钱，我会把它交付的。
Was kümmert es sie?
What do they care?
他们在乎什么？
Da hat Wade recht.
Wade's got a point, there.
韦德说得有道理。
Wenn du möchtest, übernehme ich den Anruf, Jerry.
I'll handle the call if you want, Jerry.
如果你需要的话，我会接听电话，杰瑞。
Nein, nein. Sehen Sie, sie...
No, no. See, they...
不，不。你看，他们……
Nein. Sehen Sie, sie beschäftigen sich nur mit mir.
No. See, they only deal with me.
不。你看，他们只和我打交道。
Diese Nervosität spürt man dort am Telefon.
You feel this nervousness on the phone there.
您在电话里感受到了这种紧张情绪。
Sie sind sehr ... Diese Typen sind gefährlich.
They're very...
These guys are dangerous.
他们非常……这些家伙很危险。
Ein Grund mehr. Ich will dich nicht ...
All the more reason.
I don't want you...
更有理由。我不要你……
Bei allem Respekt, Jerry, ich möchte nicht, dass Sie das vermasseln.
With all due respect, Jerry,
I don't want you mucking this up.
恕我直言，杰瑞，我不希望你把事情搞砸。
Was zum Teufel meinst du?
What the heck do you mean?
你到底是什么意思？
Sie wollen mein Geld, sie können mit mir verhandeln.
They want my money, they can deal with me.
他们想要我的钱，他们可以跟我打交道。
Ansonsten gehe ich zum Fachmann.
Otherwise,
I'm going to a professional.
否则，我要去找专业人士。
Nein, sehen Sie ... hier liegt 1 Million Dollar.
No. see...
There's $1 million here.
不，你看……这里有 100 万美元。
Nein. Sehen Sie ...
No. See...
不，看吧……
Hören Sie, Jerry, Sie verkaufen mir kein verdammtes Auto!
Look, Jerry, you're not selling me a damn car!
瞧，杰瑞，你不会卖给我一辆车！
Das ist meine Show hier. Das ist alles!
It's my show here.
That's that!
这是我的表演。就是这样！
So würden wir es lieber handhaben, Jerry.
It's the way we'd prefer to handle it, Jerry.
这是我们想要处理的方式，杰瑞。
Hallo. Wie geht es dir?
Hi. How you doing?
嗨。你好吗？
Wirklich gut. Wie geht es Ihnen heute, Ma'am?
Real good.
How are you doing today, ma'am?
非常好。女士，您今天感觉如何？
Mir geht es dort wirklich super. Danke.
I'm doing really super there. Thanks.
我在那里过得非常好。谢谢。
Ich bin Frau Gunderson. Ich habe eine Reservierung.
I'm Mrs. Gunderson.
I have a reservation.
我是冈德森太太。我有一个预订。
Ja, das tun Sie sicher, Mrs. Gunderson.
Yep.
You sure do,
Mrs. Gunderson.
是的。您确实知道，冈德森夫人。
Glauben Sie, hier unten gibt es ein Telefon?
Is there a phone down here, you think?
你觉得这里有电话吗？
Detektiv Sibert?
Detective Sibert?
西伯特侦探？
Ja, hier ist Marge Gunderson aus Brainerd. Wir haben gesprochen.
Yeah, this is Marge Gunderson from up Brainerd. We spoke.
是的，我是来自布雷纳德的玛吉·冈德森。我们聊过。
Ja. Also, eigentlich bin ich hier in der Stadt.
Yeah. Well, actually,
I'm in town here.
是的。其实我就在这儿。
Ich musste ein paar Dinge in den Twin Cities erledigen,
I had to do a few things in the Twin Cities,
我得在双城做一些事情，
also dachte ich, ich melde mich mal bei dir so I thought
I'd check in with you
所以我想和你聊聊
über die USFI-Suche nach Shep Proudfoot. about that USFI search on Shep Proudfoot.
关于 USFI 对 Shep Proudfoot 的搜索。
Oh ja?
Oh, yeah?
哦，是吗？
Nun, vielleicht besuche ich ihn, wenn ich …
Well, maybe
I'll go visit with him if I have...
好吧，如果我有时间的话，也许我会去拜访他……
Nein, das kann ich finden.
No. I can find that.
不，我能找到。
Ja. Vielen Dank.
Yeah. Well, thanks a bunch.
是的。非常感谢。
Sag, sag, weißt du zufällig
Say, say, would you happen to know
说说看，你知道吗
ein guter Ort zum Mittagessen in der Innenstadt? a good place for lunch in the downtown area?
市中心 有啥好吃午饭的地方吗？
Das Radisson.
The Radisson.
雷迪森酒店。
Ach ja? Ist das vernünftig?
Oh, yeah?
Is it reasonable?
哦，是吗？这样合理吗？
Hallo. Wie geht es dir?
Hi. How you doing?
嗨。你好吗？
Ja. Ich habe beschlossen, hier nicht zu parken.
Yeah. I decided not to park here.
是的。我决定不在这里停车。
Was soll das heißen? Du hast dich entschieden, hier nicht zu parken?
Well, what do you mean?
You decided not to park here?
那你什么意思？你决定不在这里停车了？
Ja, ich bin gerade reingekommen und habe beschlossen, hier nicht zu parken, also …
Yeah, I just came in and I decided not to park here, so...
是的，我刚进来并决定不在这里停车，所以......
Aber... Nun, es tut mir leid, Sir...
But...
Well. I'm sorry. sir...
但是...嗯，对不起，先生...
Ja, ich habe mich dagegen entschieden ... Ich ...
Yeah, I decided not to... I...
是啊，我决定不……我……
Weißt du, ich bin nicht ...
You know, I'm not...
你知道，我不是...
Wie sich herausstellte, habe ich beschlossen, die Reise nicht anzutreten, also ...
I decided not to take the trip, as it turns out, so...
事实证明，我决定不去旅行了，所以......
Es tut mir leid, Sir, wir müssen Ihnen die 4 $ trotzdem in Rechnung stellen.
Well, I'm sorry, sir, we still got to charge you the $4.
嗯，很抱歉，先生，我们仍然要向您收取 4 美元。
Ich bin gerade hier angekommen.
I just pulled in here.
我刚刚到达这里。
Ich bin verdammt nochmal gerade hier angekommen.
I just fucking pulled in here.
我他妈刚刚才到这里。
Nun, aber...
Well, but...
嗯，但是...
Sehen Sie, es gibt eine Mindestgebühr von 4 $.
See, there's a minimum charge of $4.
瞧，最低收费为 4 美元。
Langzeitparkgebühren werden tageweise berechnet.
Long-term parking charges by the day.
长期停车按天收费。
Ich schätze, Sie halten sich für eine Art Autoritätsperson.
I guess you think you're, you know, like an authority figure.
我猜你认为你像一个权威人物。
Diese beschissene Uniform, was, Kumpel?
That stupid fucking uniform, huh, buddy?
那身制服真愚蠢啊，伙计？
King Clip-On-Krawatte da.
King clip-on tie there.
那里有特大号夹式领带。
Verdammt großer Mann, was?
Big fucking man, huh?
真是个大男人啊？
Weißt du, das sind die Grenzen deines Lebens, Mann.
You know, these are the limits of your life, man.
你知道，这就是你生命的极限，老兄。
Herrscher über dein verdammtes kleines Tor hier.
Ruler of your little fucking gate here.
你是这里这座小门的统治者。
Hier. Da sind deine 4 Dollar, du erbärmliches Stück Scheiße.
Here. There's your $4, you pathetic piece of shit.
给。这是你的 4 美元，你这个可怜的家伙。
Wo ist Shep?
Where's Shep?
谢普在哪儿？
Mit einem Polizisten sprechen.
Talking to a cop.
正在和警察交谈。
Polizist?
Cop?
警察？
Sagte, sie sei Polizistin.
Said she was a cop.
说她是一名警察。
Erinnern Sie sich an den Anruf am Mittwochabend?
So do you remember getting a call
Wednesday night?
那么你记得星期三晚上接到过电话吗？
Nein.
Nope.
没有。
Sie wohnen dort in der Freemont Terrace 1425?
You do reside there at 1425 Freemont Terrace?
您确实住在 1425 Freemont Terrace 那里吗？
Ja.
Yep.
是的。
Wohnt dort noch jemand?
Anyone else residing there?
还有其他人住在那里吗？
NEIN.
No.
不。
Nun, Mr. Proudfoot, dieser Anruf kam nach 3:00 Uhr morgens.
Well, Mr. Proudfoot, this call came in past 3:00 in the morning.
嗯，普劳德富特先生，这个电话是凌晨 3 点以后打来的。
Es fällt mir einfach schwer zu glauben, dass Sie sich an keinen Anruf erinnern.
It's just hard for me to believe you don't remember anyone calling.
我只是很难相信你不记得有人打过电话。
Ich weiß, dass Sie einige Probleme hatten.
Now, I know you've had some problems.
现在，我知道你遇到了一些问题。
Kämpfe mit den Betäubungsmitteln,
Struggling with the narcotics,
与毒品斗争，
einige andere Verwicklungen, derzeit auf Bewährung. some other entanglements, currently on parole.
另有一些纠葛，目前正在假释中。
Also?
So?
所以？
Nun, der Umgang mit Kriminellen,
Well, associating with criminals,
嗯，和罪犯交往，
wenn Sie derjenige sind, mit dem sie gesprochen haben, if you're the one they talked to,
如果他们跟你谈话
das wäre ein Verstoß gegen Ihre Bewährungsauflagen. that right there would be a violation of your parole.
那样的话就会违反你的假释规定。
Sie würden wieder in Stillwater landen.
Would end you up back in Stillwater.
最终会让你回到斯蒂尔沃特。
Ich habe einiges über Ihre Vorstrafen gelesen.
Now, I saw some rough stuff on your priors,
现在，我看到了你之前的一些粗略记录，
aber nichts, was einem Mord gleichkäme. but nothing in the nature of a homicide.
但不属于谋杀性质。
Ich weiß, dass Sie bei so etwas nicht mitschuldig sein wollen.
I know you don't want to be an accessory to something like that.
我知道你不想成为这种事情的帮凶。
Sie denken also, Sie könnten sich erinnern
So, you think you might remember
所以你认为你可能还记得
wer waren die Leute, die Sie angerufen haben? who those folks were who called you?
给你打电话的人是谁？
Herr Lundegaard?
Mr. Lundegaard?
伦德加德先生？
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Könnte ich hier kurz Ihre Zeit in Anspruch nehmen?
Could I take just a minute of your time here?
我可以在这儿占用您一分钟时间吗？
Worum geht es?
What is it all about?
这到底是怎么回事？
Stört es Sie, wenn ich mich setze?
Do you mind if I sit down?
你介意我坐下吗？
Ich trage hier eine ziemliche Last.
Carrying quite a load here.
在这里承载着相当多的负荷。
Sind Sie hier der Eigentümer, Herr Lundegaard?
You're the owner here,
Mr. Lundegaard?
您是这里的老板吗，伦德加德先生？
Nein, ich ... leitender Vertriebsleiter.
No. I...
Executive Sales Manager.
不，我是……执行销售经理。
Nun, Sie können mir helfen. Mein Name ist Marge Gunderson.
Well, you can help me.
My name's Marge Gunderson.
那么，你可以帮助我。我的名字是玛吉·冈德森。
Mein Schwiegervater, er ist der Besitzer.
My father-in-law, he's the owner.
我岳父，他是老板。
Mh-hm.
Uh-huh.
嗯嗯。
Nun, ich bin ein Polizist aus Brainerd,
Well, I'm a police officer from up Brainerd,
嗯，我是来自布雷纳德的一名警察，
Untersuchung einiger Amtsvergehen. investigating some malfeasance.
调查一些渎职行为。
Und ich habe mich nur gefragt, ob Sie neue Fahrzeuge hatten
And I was just wondering if you'd had any new vehicles
我只是想知道你有没有新车
in den letzten Wochen vom Gelände gestohlen. stolen off the lot in the past couple of weeks.
过去几周内，该停车场被盗。
Insbesondere ein hellbrauner Cutlass Cierra.
Specifically a tan Cutlass Cierra.
特别是棕褐色的 Cutlass Cierra。
Herr Lundegaard.
Mr. Lundegaard.
伦德加德先生。
Brainerd.
布雷纳德。
Ja ja.
Yeah, yeah.
是啊是啊。
Heimat von Paul Bunyan, Babe, dem blauen Ochsen.
Home of Paul Bunyan,
Babe, the Blue Ox.
保罗·班扬、宝贝、蓝牛的故乡。
Babe, der blaue Ochse.
Babe, the Blue Ox.
宝贝，蓝牛。
Ja, wissen Sie, wir haben dort oben diese große Statue.
Yeah, you know, we got that big statue up there.
是的，你知道，我们在那里有一座大雕像。
Es sind Ihnen also keine Fahrzeuge abhanden gekommen?
So, you haven't had any vehicles go missing, then?
那么，你们没有遇到过任何车辆失踪的情况吗？
Nö. Nein, Ma'am.
Nope. No, ma'am.
不，不，女士。
Okay, vielen Dank.
Okey-dokey.
Thanks a bunch.
好的。非常感谢。
Dann lasse ich Sie jetzt wieder zu Ihrem Papierkram zurückkehren.
I'll let you get back to your paperwork, then.
那么我就让你回去处理你的文书工作了。
Service. Ja. Verbinde mich mit Shep.
Service.
Yeah. get me Shep.
服务。是的。帮我接 Shep。
Er ist im Moment nicht hier.
He's not here right now.
他现在不在这儿。
Was zum Teufel meinst du?
What the heck do you mean?
你到底是什么意思？
Er stieg aus.
He stepped out.
他走了出去。
Wo ist er hin? Es ist nur... Ich hole dich, Artie.
Where'd he go? It's only...
I'll get you Artie.
他去哪了？只是……我会帮你找到阿蒂。
Nein, ich brauche keinen Mechaniker. Ich brauche einen ...
No. I don't need a mechanic. I need a...
不。我不需要机械师。我需要的是……
Herrgott. Ich muss mit einem Freund von ihm reden,
Jeez. I gotta talk to a friend of his,
天哪。我得和他的一个朋友谈谈，
Also... so...
所以...
Lass ihn...
Have him...
让他...
Was?
What?
什么？
Oh, Herrgott.
Oh, jeez.
噢，天哪。
Mikrofon?
Mike?
麦克风？
Marge?
玛吉？
Herrje! Oh, du siehst toll aus!
Jeez! Oh, you look great!
天哪！噢，你看上去棒极了！
Ja. 80, oder? Immer mit der Ruhe. Immer mit der Ruhe ...
Yeah. 80 do you.
Easy there. Easy...
是的。你 80 岁了。放轻松。放轻松……
Immer mit der Ruhe. Immer mit der Ruhe. Du auch.
Easy there.
You do, too.
放轻松。放轻松。你也是。
Ich bin jetzt schwanger.
I'm expecting now.
我現在正在期盼。
Ich sehe das. Das ist großartig.
I see that.
That's great.
我明白了。太好了。
Was kann ich Ihnen bringen?
What can I get you?
我能为您做些什么？
Nur eine Diet Coke, bitte.
Just a Diet Coke, please.
只需一杯健怡可乐就行。
Großartig.
Great.
伟大的。
Das ist ein schöner Ort.
This is a nice place.
这是一个好地方。
Ja. Es ist das Radisson, also ziemlich gut.
Yeah. You know, it's the Radisson, so it's pretty good.
是的。你知道，这是雷迪森酒店，所以它相当不错。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Also...
So...
所以...
Sie leben also in Edina?
You're living in Edina, then?
那么，您住在伊迪纳吗？
Ja, ja, ja. Seit ein paar Jahren.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
A couple of years now.
是的，是的，是的。已经有几年了。
Es ist eigentlich Eden Prairie.
It's actually
Eden Prairie.
它实际上是伊甸草原。
Dieser Schulbezirk.
That school district.
那个学区。
80, Chief Gunderson, also!
80, Chief Gunderson, then!
那么，80，冈德森局长！
Also hast du Norm, den Sohn eines Gunderson, geheiratet.
So, you went and married
Norm son-of-a-Gunderson.
所以，你就嫁给了冈德森的儿子诺姆。
Oh ja. Vor langer Zeit.
Oh, yeah.
Long time ago.
哦，是的。很久以前。
Großartig, großartig.
Great, great.
很好，很好。
Also, was bringt Sie runter?
So, what brings you down?
那么，什么事让你情绪低落？
Sind Sie hier unten wegen des Mordes,
Are you down here on that homicide,
你来这里是为了那起凶杀案吗？
wenn es Ihnen erlaubt ist, darüber zu sprechen? if you're allowed, you know, to discuss that?
如果你被允许讨论这个的话？
Oh, ja, ja.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
哦，是的，是的。
Aber es gibt nicht viel zu besprechen.
But there's not a heck of a lot to discuss.
但其实并没有太多可讨论的内容。
Okay.
好的。
Und, was ist mit dir, Mike?
Well, what about you, Mike?
那么你呢，迈克？
Sind Sie verheiratet?
Are you married?
你结婚了吗？
Du hast Kinder?
You got kids?
你有孩子吗？
Ja, ja. Also...
Yeah, yeah. Well...
是啊，是啊。嗯……
Ich war verheiratet. Ich war verheiratet mit...
I was married.
I was married to...
我结婚了。我嫁给了……
Stört es Sie, wenn ich mich hier hinsetze?
You mind if I sit over here?
你介意我坐在这儿吗？
Ich war mit Linda Cooksey verheiratet.
I was married to Linda Cooksey.
我和琳达·库克西结婚了。
Nein. Setz dich doch da drüben hin. Das ist mir lieber.
No. Why don't you sit over there?
I prefer that.
不。你为什么不坐在那边？我更喜欢那边。
Okay.
好的。
Entschuldigung.
Sorry.
对不起。
Nein, nein. Nur damit ich dich sehen kann. Ich muss mich nicht umdrehen.
No. no.
Just so I can see you.
Don't have to turn my neck.
不，不。只要我能看见你。不用扭过我的脖子。
Sicher, sicher. Ich verstehe.
Sure, sure. I understand.
当然，当然。我明白。
Ich wollte nicht ...
I didn't mean to...
我不是故意的...
Nein, nein. Das ist in Ordnung.
No, no. That's fine.
不，不。没关系。
Ja, tut mir leid. Tut mir leid.
Yeah, sorry. Sorry.
是的，抱歉。抱歉。
Also, ich war mit Linda Cooksey verheiratet.
So, I was married to Linda Cooksey.
所以，我和琳达·库克西结婚了。
Du erinnerst dich an Linda. Sie war ein Jahr hinter uns.
You remember Linda.
She was a year behind us.
你记得琳达吗？她比我们小一年级。
Ja. Ich glaube, ich erinnere mich an sie.
Yeah. I think
I remember her.
是的。我想我记得她。
Ja! Sie... Oh, ja!
Yeah! She...
Oh, yeah!
是啊！她…噢，是啊！
Also, es hat nicht geklappt, oder?
So, it didn't work out, huh?
所以，事情没成功，是吧？
Und dann arbeite ich jetzt seit ein paar Jahren für Honeywell.
And then I've been working for Honeywell for a few years now.
现在我已经在霍尼韦尔工作了几年。
Nun, sie sind ein gutes Outfit.
Well, they're a good outfit.
嗯，他们的服装很不错。
Ja, wenn Sie Ingenieur sind, ja, dann könnten Sie es viel schlechter treffen.
Yeah, if you're an engineer, yeah, you could do a lot worse.
是的，如果你是一名工程师，你的情况可能会更糟。
Aber das ist es nicht...
But it's not...
但事实并非如此...
Es ist nichts im Vergleich zu Ihrer Leistung.
It's nothing like your achievement.
这和你的成就完全不一样。
Also, es hört sich an, als ob es dir wirklich super geht.
Well, it sounds like you're doing really super.
嗯，听起来你做得非常棒。
Es ist nicht so...
It's not that...
不是那樣...
Es ist nicht so, dass es nicht geklappt hätte. Es ist ...
It's not that things didn't work out. It's...
并不是说事情没有进展。而是……
Linda hatte Leukämie, wissen Sie.
Linda had leukemia, you know.
你知道，琳达患有白血病。
Sie war... Sie ist gestorben.
She was...
She passed away.
她......她去世了。
NEIN.
No.
不。
Es war hart.
It was tough.
这很艰难。
Da haben Sie es.
There you go.
就这样。
Es war lang...
It was long...
很长...
Sie hat wirklich hart gekämpft, Marge.
She fought real hard, Marge.
她确实努力奋斗了，玛吉。
Du weisst...
You know...
你知道...
Also, was können Sie sagen?
So, what can you say?
那么，你能说什么呢？
Bessere Zeiten, was?
Better times, huh?
那是更好的时光，嗯？
Bessere Zeiten.
Better times.
更好的时光。
Und dann habe ich Sie im Fernsehen gesehen und mich erinnert, wissen Sie?
And then I saw you on the TV and I remembered, you know?
然后我在电视上看到你，我就想起来了，你知道吗？
Ich mochte dich immer.
I always liked you.
我一直很喜欢你。
Also, ich mochte dich immer ...
Well, I always liked you...
嗯，我一直都很喜欢你……
Ich mochte dich immer so sehr.
I always liked you so much.
我一直很喜欢你。
Also, Mike, was meinst du, sollten wir uns ein anderes Mal treffen?
So, Mike, should we get together another time, you think?
那么，迈克，你觉得我们应该改天再聚吗？
ALSO...
NOH...
出色地...
Es tut mir leid. Es ist...
I'm sorry. It's...
抱歉，这是……
Wissen Sie, ich hätte das nicht tun sollen.
You know,
I shouldn't have done this.
你知道，我不应该这么做。
Ich hätte das nicht tun sollen. Ich sollte nicht.
I shouldn't have done this.
I shouldn't.
我不该这么做。我不该这么做。
Ich dachte, wir würden eine wirklich tolle Zeit haben.
I thought we'd have a really terrific time.
我以为我们将会度过一段非常愉快的时光。
Es ist okay, Mike.
It's okay, Mike.
没关系，迈克。
Du warst so eine tolle Frau.
You were such a super lady.
你真是一个超级女人。
Und dann ... war ich so einsam.
And then...
I've been so lonely.
然后...我就感觉很孤独。
Es ist okay, Mike.
It's okay, Mike.
没关系，迈克。
Hier ist ein Lied, das ich allen Damen hier heute Abend widme.
Here's a song
I dedicate to all the ladies out here tonight.
这是我献给今晚在场的所有女士的一首歌。
Geht so.
Goes like this.
就像这样。
Lass uns heute Abend zueinander finden
Let's find each other tonight
今晚我们相见吧
Alles wird gut
Everything will be all right
一切都会好起来的
Zögern Sie jetzt nicht
Don't hesitate now
现在不要犹豫
Lass uns heute Abend zueinander finden
Let's find each other tonight
今晚我们相见吧
Also...
So...
所以...
Bist du von hier?
Are you from around here?
你是这儿人吗？
Bin nur geschäftlich in der Stadt.
Just in town on business.
只是来城里出差。
Einfach rein und raus.
Just in and out.
刚进刚出。
Nur ein bisschen vom alten Rein und Raus.
Just a little of the old in-and-out.
只是一些旧的进出。
Was machst du?
What do you do?
你做什么工作？
ICH...
I...
我...
Waren Sie schon einmal im Celebrity Room?
You been to the Celebrity Room before?
您以前去过名人室吗？
Mit anderen Kunden?
With other clients?
和其他客户一起吗？
Ich glaube nicht.
I don't think so.
我不这么认为。
Es ist schön.
It's nice.
非常好。
Ja, nun, es hängt vom Künstler ab.
Yeah, well, depends on the artist.
是的，这取决于艺术家。
Wissen Sie, Jose Feliciano, Sie haben keine Beschwerden.
You know, Jose Feliciano, you got no complaints.
你知道，何塞·费利西亚诺，你没有什么可抱怨的。
Kellner!
Waiter!
服务员！
Was ist er, taub?
What is he, deaf?
他怎么了？聋子吗？
Also...
So...
所以...
Wie lange arbeitest du für den Escortservice?
How long you work for the escort service?
您从事陪护服务工作多长时间了？
Ich weiß nicht. Ein paar Monate.
I don't know.
A few months.
我不知道。几个月吧。
Finden Sie diese Arbeit interessant, oder?
Find that work interesting, do you?
你觉得那项工作很有趣吗？
Worüber redest du?
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Rechts.
Right.
正确的。
Aufleuchten.
Come on.
快点。
Ich höre Glocken. Komm schon.
I'm hearing bells.
Come on.
我听到铃声了。快来吧。
Alles klar. Wo warst du?
All right.
Where were you?
好的。你当时在哪儿？
Shep, was zur Hölle machst du da? Ich knall das Mädchen.
Shep, what the hell are you doing?
I'm banging that girl.
谢普，你到底在干什么？我要跟那个女孩上床。
Verdammtes Arschloch. Verschwinde von hier.
Fucking asshole.
Get the fuck out of here.
他妈的混蛋。滚出去。
Bring mich zurück nach Stillwater, du kleines Scheißkerl.
Put me back in Stillwater, you little fucking shithead.
把我送回斯蒂尔沃特，你这个混蛋。
Verschwinde von hier.
Get the fuck out of here.
滚出去。
Yo! Hör auf mit dem Scheiß, Mann.
Yo!
Cut that shit out, man.
哟！别再胡闹了，老兄。
Ich versuche hier verdammt noch mal, ein bisschen Schlaf zu bekommen.
Trying to get some goddamn sleep here.
想在这里好好睡一觉。
Komm schon, Bruder ...
Come on, brother...
来吧，兄弟……
Fick dich!
Fuck you!
去你的！
Fick dich.
Fuck you.
去你的。
Tiere!
Animals!
动物！
Bleib mir fern, Mann.
Stay away from me, man.
离我远点，伙计。
Hey, rauch eine verdammte Friedenspfeife!
Hey, smoke a fucking peace pipe!
嘿，抽根他妈的和平烟斗！
Wage es ja nicht, mich zu schlagen!
Don't you dare fucking hit me!
你他妈不许打我！
Verdammtes kleines Wiesel!
Fucking little weasel!
他妈的小黄鼠狼！
Fick dich, Mann. Hör auf!
Fuck you. man.
Stop it!
去你丫的。哥们。别再这样了！
Du verdammter, verfluchter, verfluchter Hurensohn, du verdammter Schwanz!
You fucking, motherfucking, son-of-a-bitching, fucking cock!
你这个操蛋的、狗娘养的、操蛋的鸡巴！
Herrgott noch mal! Du verdammtes Arschloch, Wichser!
Jesus Christ! You fucking shitbag motherfucker!
天啊！你这个混蛋！
Ja?
Yeah?
是的？
Also gut, Jerry, ich habe genug vom Herumficken.
All right, Jerry,
I'm through fucking around.
好了，杰瑞，我不再胡闹了。
Hast du das verdammte Geld?
You got the fucking money?
你他妈有钱吗？
Ja, ich habe das Geld, aber ...
Yeah, I got the money, but...
是的，我拿到了钱，但是......
Mach es verdammt nochmal nicht mit mir, Jerry.
Don't you fucking but me, Jerry.
别跟我做爱，杰瑞。
Ich möchte, dass Sie dieses Geld in die Parkrampe des Dayton Radisson legen, oberste Ebene,
I want you to put this money in the Dayton Radisson parking ramp, top level,
我要你把这笔钱放在代顿雷迪森停车场的顶层，
30 Minuten, Jerry, wir bringen die Sache zum Abschluss.
30 minutes, Jerry, we wrap this thing up.
30 分钟，杰瑞，我们把这件事结束了。
Okay. Aber...
Okay. But...
好吧。但是...
Hey, du bist in 30 Minuten da, oder ich finde dich, Jerry,
Hey, you're there in 30 minutes or I find you, Jerry,
嘿，你 30 分钟后就到，不然我就找到你了，杰瑞，
und ich erschieße dich und ich erschieße deine verdammte Frau, and I shoot you and
I shoot your fucking wife,
然后我就开枪打死你和你的老婆，
und ich erschieße alle eure verdammten kleinen Kinder and I shoot all your little fucking children
我会枪毙你们所有的孩子
und ich schieße ihnen allen in den Hinterkopf. Verstanden? and I shoot them all in the back of their little fucking heads. You got it?
然后我就把他们全部射到他们的后脑勺上。你懂了吗？
Okay, und jetzt bleib weg von Scotty.
Okay, now, you stay away from Scotty, now.
好的，现在你离斯科蒂远点。
Habe es?
Got it?
知道了？
Okay. Also wirklich gut.
Okay. Real good, then.
好的。那么，真的很棒。
Papa.
Dad.
爸爸。
Es ist okay, Scotty.
It's okay, Scotty.
没关系，斯科蒂。
Wo gehst du hin?
Where you going?
你要去哪儿？
Ich bin gleich wieder da.
I'll be back in a minute.
我马上回来。
Wenn Stan anruft, sagen Sie ihm einfach, dass ich zu Embers gegangen bin.
If Stan calls, you just tell him
I went to Embers.
如果斯坦打电话来，你就告诉他我去了 Embers。
Okay.
好的。
Hier ist dein verdammtes Geld.
Here's your damn money.
这是你的钱。
Und wo ist meine Tochter?
Now, where's my daughter?
那么，我的女儿在哪儿？
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Du verdammter Punk!
You goddamn punk!
你这个该死的小混蛋！
Wer zum Teufel bist du?
Who the fuck are you?
你他妈是谁？
Wer zum Teufel bist du?
Who the fuck are you?
你他妈是谁？
Ich habe dein verdammtes Geld. Und wo ist meine Tochter?
I got your damn money.
Now, where's my daughter?
我拿走了你的钱。现在，我的女儿在哪儿？
Ich habe genug vom Herumficken!
I am through fucking around!
我受够了！
Lass den verdammten Aktenkoffer fallen!
Drop that fucking briefcase!
把那个该死的公文包放下！
Wo ist meine Tochter?
Where's my daughter?
我的女儿在哪儿？
Fick dich, Mann! Wo ist Jerry?
Fuck you, man!
Where's Jerry?
去你妈的，哥们！杰瑞在哪？
Ich habe verdammt einfache Anweisungen gegeben.
I gave simple fucking instructions.
我给出了简单的指示。
Wo ist meine verdammte Tochter?
Where's my damn daughter?
我该死的女儿在哪儿？
Kein Jean, kein Geld.
No Jean, no money.
没有 Jean，就没有钱。
Lass das verdammte Geld fallen!
Drop that fucking money!
把那该死的钱扔掉！
Nein, Jean, kein Geld!
No Jean, no money!
没有 Jean，就没有钱！
Ist das hier ein verdammter Witz?
Is this a fucking joke here?
这他妈是开玩笑吗？
Oh, Herrgott.
Oh, jeez.
噢，天哪。
Bist du jetzt glücklich, Arschloch?
You happy now, asshole?
你现在开心了吗，混蛋？
Was ist mit euch Leuten los?
What's with you people?
你们这是怎么了？
Ihr verdammten Idioten!
You fucking imbeciles!
你们这群他妈的白痴！
Du hast verdammt nochmal auf mich geschossen!
You fucking shot me!
你他妈开枪打我！
Kann ich bitte Ihre Fahrkarte haben?
May I have your ticket, please?
我可以拿一下您的票吗？
Mach das verdammte Tor auf!
Open the fucking gate!
打开他妈的门！
Oh, Herrgott.
Oh, jeez.
噢，天哪。
Papa?
Dad?
爸爸？
Ja?
Yeah?
是的？
Stan Grossman hat angerufen.
Stan Grossman called.
斯坦·格罗斯曼打来电话。
Ja. Okay.
Yeah. Okay.
嗯，好的。
Zweimal.
Twice.
两次。
Okay.
好的。
Ist alles in Ordnung?
Is everything okay?
一切都还好吗？
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Rufst du Stan an?
Are you calling Stan?
你在给斯坦打电话吗？
Also, ich bin...
Well, I'm...
嗯，我...
Ich gehe jetzt ins Bett.
I'm going to bed now.
我要睡觉了。
Wie geht's?
How you doing?
你好吗？
Herr Mohra? Ja?
Mr. Mohra?
Yeah?
莫赫拉先生？是吗？
Offizier Olson.
Officer Olson.
奥尔森警官。
Ja, genau.
Yeah. Righto.
是啊。没错。
Also...
Well...
出色地...
Also, ich habe letzten Dienstag bei Ecklund und Swedlin's als Barkeeper gearbeitet,
So I'm tending bar down there at Ecklund and
Swedlin's last Tuesday,
上周二我在 Ecklund and Swedlin's 酒吧当酒保，
und dieser kleine Kerl trinkt, and this little guy's drinking,
这个小家伙在喝酒，
und er sagt: „Wo kann ein Kerl etwas Action finden? and he says,
"Where can a guy find some action?
他说，“一个人在哪里可以找到一些行动呢？
„Ich werde da draußen am See verrückt.“
"I'm going crazy out there at the lake."
“我在湖边快要疯了。”
Und ich sage: „Was für eine Aktion?“
And I says,
"What kind of action?"
我说：“什么样的行动？”
Und er sagt: „Frauen-Action. Wie sehe ich aus?“
And he says,
"Woman action.
What do I look like?"
然后他说：“女人，行动起来。我长得什么样？”
Und ich sage: „Also, wie sehe ich aus?
And I says,
"Well, what do
I look like?
我说：“那么，我长得什么样？
„So etwas arrangiere ich nicht.“
"I don't arrange that kind of thing."
“我不安排那种事。”
Und er sagt: „Aber ich werde da draußen am See verrückt.“
And he says,
"But I'm going crazy out there at the lake."
他说：“但是在湖边我快要疯了。”
Und ich sage: „Ja, aber das ist nicht so ein Ort.“
And I says,
"Yeah, but this ain't that kind of place.”
我说：“是啊，但这不是那种地方。”
Er sagt: „Oh, das verstehe ich. Sie halten mich also für einen Idioten, weil ich frage.“
He says, "Oh, so I get it.
So you think I'm some kind of jerk for asking."
他说：“哦，我明白了。所以你认为我问这个问题很混蛋吗？”
Nur benutzt er nicht das Wort „Idiot“.
Only he don't use the word "jerk."
只是他不使用“混蛋”这个词。
Ich verstehe. Dann nennt er mich einen Idioten.
I understand.
Then he calls me a jerk.
我明白了。然后他骂我是混蛋。
Sagt, der letzte Typ, der ihn für einen Idioten hielt, ist jetzt tot.
Says the last guy thought he's a jerk is dead now.
说最后那个以为自己是混蛋的家伙现在已经死了。
Also sage ich nichts.
So, I don't say nothing.
所以，我什么也没说。
Er sagt: „Was denkst du darüber?“
He says,
"What do you think about that?"
他说：“你对此有什么看法？”
Und ich sage: „Na ja, das klingt dann nicht nach einem allzu guten Geschäft für ihn.“
And I says, "Well, that don't sound like too good a deal for him, then."
我说：“那么，这对他来说听起来不太好。”
Das hast du richtig verstanden.
You got that right.
你说对了。
Ja, er sagt: „Ja, der Typ ist tot,
Yeah, he says,
"Yeah, that guy's dead,
是的，他说，“是的，那家伙死了，
„und ich meine nicht das Alter.“
"and I don't mean of old age."
“我并不是指年老。”
Und dann sagt er: „Meine Güte, ich werde da draußen am See verrückt.“
And then he says,
"Jeez, I'm going crazy out there at the lake."
然后他说：“天哪，我在湖边快要疯了。”
Weißer Bärensee?
White Bear Lake?
白熊湖？
Ja, also, bei Ecklund und Swedlin, das ist näher am Moose Lake.
Yeah, well, at Ecklund and Swedlin, that's closer to Moose Lake.
是的，在 Ecklund 和 Swedlin，那里离 Moose 湖更近一些。
Also bin ich von dieser Annahme ausgegangen.
So I made that assumption.
所以我做出了这个假设。
Sicher.
Sure.
当然。
Wie auch immer, er trinkt an der Bar,
Anyway, he's drinking at the bar,
不管怎样，他在酒吧喝酒，
also ich halte nicht viel davon, so I don't think a whole great deal of it,
所以我并不觉得这有什么大不了的，
Aber dann hörte Frau Mohra von den Morden hier unten but then Mrs. Mohra, she heard about the homicides down here
但后来莫赫拉夫人听说了这里发生的凶杀案
und dachte, ich sollte es melden, also habe ich es gemeldet. and thought
I should call it in, so I called it in.
我认为我应该报警，所以我就报警了。
Ende der Geschichte.
End of story.
故事结束。
Also, wie sah dieser Typ überhaupt aus?
Well, what'd this guy look like, anyways?
那么，这个人到底长什么样？
Oh, er ist ein...
Oh, he's a...
噢，他是个...
Kleiner Kerl, sieht irgendwie komisch aus.
Little guy, kind of funny-looking.
小家伙，看上去有点滑稽。
Inwiefern?
In what way?
以什么方式？
Nur ganz allgemein.
Just in a general kind of way.
只是一般意义上。
Okay. Vielen Dank, Herr Mohra.
Okay.
Well. thanks a bunch,
Mr. Mohra.
好的。非常感谢，莫赫拉先生。
Du hast recht. Es ist wahrscheinlich nichts,
You're right.
It's probably nothing,
你说得对。可能没什么，
aber danke, dass Sie sie gerufen haben. but thanks for calling her in.
但谢谢你叫她来。
Sicher.
Sure.
当然。
Sieht aus, als würde ihr morgen kalt werden.
Looks like she's gonna turn cold tomorrow.
看来她明天会变冷。
Oh ja. Da kommt eine Front rein.
Oh, yeah.
Got a front coming in.
噢，是的。前面有人进来了。
Ja, das hast du richtig verstanden.
Yeah.
You got that right.
是的。你说对了。
Jesus Christus.
Jesus Christ.
耶稣基督。
Valerie, ich fahre heute Morgen zurück nach Brainerd.
Valerie,
I'm leaving this morning, back up to Brainerd.
瓦莱丽，我今天早上要离开，返回布雷纳德。
Es tut mir leid, dass ich Sie nicht sehen werde.
Well, I'm sorry
I won't see you.
嗯，很遗憾我不能见你。
Aber Sie glauben, es geht ihm gut?
But you think he's all right?
但你认为他还好吗？
Ich habe ihn gestern Abend gesehen und ...
I saw him last night and...
我昨晚见到他了并且……
Was hat er gesagt?
What did he say?
他说了啥？
Nun, er hat nichts Konkretes gesagt.
Well, it's nothing specific he said.
嗯，他没有具体说什么。
Es schien, als hätte ihn der Tod seiner Frau wirklich hart getroffen.
It just seemed like it all hit him really hard, his wife dying.
他的妻子去世了，这一切似乎对他的打击非常大。
Seine Frau? Linda.
His wife?
Linda.
他的妻子？琳达。
Wer? Linda Cooksey.
Who?
Linda Cooksey.
谁？琳达·库克西。
Nein. Nein, nein. Sie waren nicht ...
No. No, no.
They weren't...
不，不，不，他们不是……
Er hat Linda ungefähr... ein gutes Jahr lang belästigt.
He was bothering Linda for about...
For a good year.
他已经困扰琳达大约...有一年了。
Ich habe sie wirklich belästigt und sie nicht in Ruhe gelassen.
Really pestering her, wouldn't leave her alone.
真的缠着她，不肯放过她。
Also...
So...
所以...
Er hat nicht...
He didn't...
他没...
Er hat nie...
He never...
他從不...
Nein! Nein, sie haben nie geheiratet.
No! No, they never married.
不！不，他们从未结婚。
Mike hatte psychische Probleme.
Mike's had psychiatric problems.
迈克有精神问题。
Oh, meine Güte.
Oh, my.
噢，我的天。
Ja, er hatte zu kämpfen.
Yeah, he's been struggling.
是的，他一直在努力。
Er lebt jetzt bei seinen Eltern.
He's living with his parents now.
他现在和父母住在一起。
Oh, Herrgott.
Oh, jeez.
噢，天哪。
Linda geht es gut. Du solltest sie anrufen.
Linda's fine.
You should call her.
Linda 很好。你应该给她打电话。
Herrgott. Also...
Jeez. Well...
天哪。好吧……
Herrgott.
Jeez.
天哪。
Das ist eine Überraschung.
That's a surprise.
这真是一个惊喜。
Hallo!
Hello!
你好！
Herr Lundegaard, entschuldigen Sie die erneute Störung. Darf ich reinkommen?
Mr. Lundegaard, sorry to bother you again.
Can I come in?
伦德加德先生，很抱歉再次打扰您。我可以进来吗？
Ja ... Nein. Ich bin hier ziemlich beschäftigt.
Yeah... No.
I'm kind of busy here.
是啊...不。我在这里有点忙。
Ich verstehe. Dann mache ich es ganz kurz.
I understand.
I'll keep it real short, then.
我明白了。那我就长话短说吧。
Ich bin auf dem Weg aus der Stadt, aber ich habe mich gefragt ...
I'm on my way out of town, but I was wondering...
我正要出城，但我在想......
Stört es Sie, wenn ich mich setze?
Do you mind if I sit down?
你介意我坐下吗？
Ich trage hier eine ziemliche Last.
Carrying a bit of a load here.
在这里承受了一点负担。
Nein, ich...
No, I...
不，我……
Ja, es ist dieses Fahrzeug, nach dem ich gestern gefragt habe.
Yeah, it's this vehicle
I asked about yesterday.
是的，这就是我昨天问到的这辆车。
Ich habe mich nur gefragt ...
I was just wondering...
我只是想知道……
Ja, wie ich Ihnen sagte, es sind bei uns keine Fahrzeuge verschwunden.
Yeah, like I told you, we haven't had any vehicles go missing.
是的，正如我告诉你的，我们没有任何车辆失踪。
Okay. Bist du sicher?
Okay. Are you sure?
好的。你确定吗？
Denn ich meine, woher weißt du das?
'Cause I mean, how do you know?
'因为我的意思是，你怎么知道？
Denn sehen Sie, das Verbrechen, das ich untersuche,
Because, see, the crime
I'm investigating,
因为，你看，我正在调查的犯罪案件，
die Täter fuhren ein Auto mit Händlerkennzeichen, the perpetrators were driving a car with dealer plates,
肇事者驾驶一辆挂有经销商牌照的汽车，
und sie riefen jemanden an, der hier arbeitet, and they called someone who works here,
他们打电话给在这里工作的人，
Es wäre also ein ziemlicher Zufall, wenn das nicht der Fall wäre. so it'd be quite a coincidence if they weren't,
如果不是，那也只是巧合而已，
Sie wissen schon, verbunden. you know, connected.
你知道，连接了。
Ja, ich verstehe.
Yeah, I see.
是的，我明白。
Also, wie geht es Ihnen...
So, how do you...
那么，你如何...
Haben Sie vor Kurzem eine Inventur durchgeführt?
Have you done any kind of inventory recently?
您最近做过任何类型的盘点吗？
Das Auto ist nicht von unserem Gelände, Ma'am.
The car's not from our lot, ma'am.
这辆车不是我们公司的，女士。
Aber wie können Sie das sicher wissen, ohne …
But how do you know that for sure without doing a...
但是如果不做的话你怎么能确定呢？
Nun, ich würde es wissen.
Well, I would know.
嗯，我知道。
Ich bin der Executive Sales Manager.
I'm the Executive
Sales Manager.
我是执行销售经理。
Ja, aber ich verstehe ...
Yeah, but I understand...
是的，但我明白……
Wir führen hier ein ziemlich strenges Regiment.
We run a pretty tight ship here.
我们这里的管理相当严格。
Ich weiß, aber...
I know, but...
我知道，但是...
Nun, wie stellen sie das fest, Sir?
Well, how do they establish that, sir?
那么，先生，他们如何证实这一点呢？
Ich meine. Werden die Autos täglich gezählt?
I mean.
Are the cars counted daily.
我是说。每天都会统计车辆数量吗？
Oder was für eine Routine gibt es hier?
Or what kind of a routine here?
或者这里有什么样的惯例？
Ma'am, ich habe Ihre Frage beantwortet.
Ma'am, I answered your question.
女士，我回答了您的问题。
Wie bitte, Sir?
I'm sorry, sir?
抱歉，先生？
Ma'am, ich habe Ihre Frage beantwortet.
Ma'am, I answered your question.
女士，我回答了您的问题。
Ich habe das verdammte Ding beantwortet ...
I answered the darn...
我回答该死的……
Ich kooperiere hier und es gibt kein ...
I'm cooperating here, and there's no...
我在这里合作，而且没有......
Sir, Sie haben keinen Grund, schnippisch zu mir zu sein.
Sir, you have no call to get snippy with me.
先生，您没必要对我这么不耐烦。
Ich mache hier nur meinen Job.
I'm just doing my job here.
我只是在做我的工作。
Ich bin...
I'm...
我是...
Ich bin nicht ... ich streite hier nicht.
I'm not...
I'm not arguing here.
我不是......我不是在这里争论。
Ich kooperiere und es gibt kein ...
I'm cooperating, and there's no...
我正在合作，而且没有......
Wir tun alles, was wir können.
We're doing all we can.
我们正在尽一切努力。
Sir, könnte ich mit Herrn Gustafson sprechen?
Sir, could I talk to Mr. Gustafson?
先生，我可以和古斯塔夫森先生通话吗？
Herr Lundegaard.
Mr. Lundegaard.
伦德加德先生。
Na, zum Teufel! Wenn du willst... Wenn du hier spielen willst,
Well, heck! If you wanna...
If you wanna play games here,
好吧，见鬼！如果你想……如果你想在这里玩游戏，
Ich arbeite mit Ihnen an dieser Sache hier, aber ...
I'm working with you on this thing here, but...
我正在和你一起处理这件事，但是......
Okay! Ich werde verdammt viel zählen!
Okay!
I'll do a damn lot count!
好的！我会好好数一数的！
Sir, sofort?
Sir, right now?
先生，现在就好吗？
Genau jetzt.
Yeah! Right now.
是的！现在就好。
Du tust verdammt nochmal!
You're darn tooting!
你吹得真他妈的响！
Wenn es dir so verdammt wichtig ist.
If it's so damned important to you.
如果它对你来说如此重要。
Es tut mir leid, Sir.
Well, I'm sorry, sir.
嗯，很抱歉，先生。
Was zum Teufel! Herrgott!
What the Christ! Jeez!
什么基督啊！天啊！
Bob Elcorona, Zeile zwei.
Bob Elcorona, line two.
鲍勃·埃尔科罗纳，二号线。
Um Himmels Willen.
For Pete's sake.
看在上帝的份上。
Um Himmels willen, er flieht vor dem Interview.
For Pete's sake, he's fleeing the interview.
老天爷啊，他逃避面试了。
Er flieht vor dem Interview!
He's fleeing the interview!
他正在逃避面试！
Wie bekomme ich hier eine Amtsholung?
How do I get an outside line here?
我怎样才能在这里拨打外线？
In Ordnung.
All right.
好的。
Ja. Detective Sibert, bitte.
Yeah.
Detective Sibert, please.
是的。请叫我西伯特侦探。
Ich habe Ihnen gesagt, dass es vorbei ist, und ich dachte, ich hätte mich sehr deutlich ausgedrückt.
I told you it was over, and I thought
I made myself very clear.
我告诉过你一切都结束了，我想我已经说得很清楚了。
Oh, das hast du. Du hast dich vollkommen klar ausgedrückt.
Oh, you did.
You made yourself perfectly clear.
哦，你说得对。你说得很清楚了。
Aber es ist etwas dazwischengekommen.
But something's come up.
但有事发生了。
Was?
What?
什么？
Nun, es ist etwas ziemlich Kleines,
Well, it's something kind of small,
嗯，这是一件小事，
aber es könnte ein großes Problem sein. but it might be a big problem.
但这可能是一个大问题。
Ich bin schwanger.
I'm pregnant.
我怀孕了。
Ich bin schwanger.
I'm pregnant.
我怀孕了。
Ich habe einen Arzttest gemacht, ich habe das Zertifikat,
I've had a doctor's test,
I've got the certificate,
我已经做过医生检查，拿到了证明，
und daran besteht kein Zweifel. Ich werde dein Baby bekommen. and there's no doubt about it.
I'm gonna have your baby.
毫无疑问，我会为你怀上孩子。
Schauen Sie mal hier. Ich kann das erklären.
Now, look here.
I can explain this.
现在看这里。我可以解释这一点。
Sehen Sie, Robin war... ist einer meiner Schüler.
See, Robin was...
Is a student of mine.
瞧，罗宾是......是我的学生。
Du solltest den anderen Kerl sehen.
You should see the other guy.
你应该见见另一个人。
Nein, nein, nein. So etwas war es nicht.
No, no, no.
It wasn't anything like that.
不不不，根本不是那样。
Du verstehst das nicht!
You don't understand!
你不明白！
Ich habe den Brief gelesen, den sie geschrieben hat.
I read that letter that she wrote.
我读了她写的那封信。
Ich glaube, ich habe alles verstanden ...
I think I understand all there is...
我想我明白了一切......
Was ist mit ihr passiert?
What happened to her?
她怎么了？
Sie fing an zu schreien, wissen Sie.
She started shrieking, you know.
你知道，她开始尖叫。
Herrgott.
Jeez.
天哪。
Nun, ich habe das Geld bekommen.
Well, I got the money.
嗯，我拿到钱了。
Alles, insgesamt 80 Riesen.
All of it, all 80 grand.
全部，总共8万美元。
Das sind 40 für dich, 40 für mich.
That's 40 for you,
40 for me.
那你给 40，我给 40。
Das war's dann.
That's it, then.
就这样吧。
Du kannst meinen Truck haben.
You can have my truck.
我的卡车你可以用。
Ich nehme die Cierra.
I'm taking the Cierra.
我要乘坐 Cierra。
Das teilen wir uns.
We split that.
我们分开了。
Wie zum Teufel zerlegt man ein verdammtes Auto, du Idiot?
How the fuck do you split a fucking car, you dummy?
你这个笨蛋，到底是怎么把一辆汽车拆开的？
Mit einer verdammten Kettensäge?
With a fucking chain saw?
用他妈的链锯？
Einer von uns bezahlt dem anderen die Hälfte.
One of us pays the other for half.
我们其中一个人支付另一人一半的费用。
Moment mal. Auf keinen Fall.
Hold on.
No fucking way.
等等，不可能。
Ist dir das verdammt noch mal aufgefallen?
Did you fucking notice this?
你他妈注意到了这一点吗？
Ich wurde verdammt nochmal angeschossen!
I got fucking shot!
我他妈中枪了！
Mir wurde verdammt nochmal ins Gesicht geschossen!
I got fucking shot in the face!
我他妈的脸被击中了！
Ich bin hingegangen und habe das verdammte Geld geholt!
I went and got the fucking money!
我去拿那该死的钱了！
Ich wurde beim Aufheben erschossen!
I got shot fucking picking it up!
我捡起它时被枪击了！
Ich bin seit verdammten 36 Stunden wach!
I've been up for 36 fucking hours!
我已经 36 个小时没睡了！
Ich nehme dieses verdammte Auto!
I'm taking that fucking car!
我要开那辆他妈的车！
Das Ding gehört mir, du verdammtes Arschloch.
That fuck is mine, you fucking asshole.
那他妈的是我的，你这个混蛋。
Weißt du, ich habe mir deinen verdammten Schwachsinn die ganze Woche angehört!
You know, I've been listening to your fucking bullshit all week!
你知道吗，我整个星期都在听你的胡言乱语！
Sind wir ehrlich?
Are we square?
我们是正方形的吗？
Sind wir ehrlich?
Are we square?
我们是正方形的吗？
Ja, du verdammter Stummer!
Yeah, you fucking mute!
是啊，你这个该死的哑巴！
Und wenn Sie Ihren Freund Shep Proudfoot sehen,
And if you see your friend,
Shep Proudfoot,
如果你看到你的朋友谢普·普劳德福特，
sag ihm, dass ich ihm seinen verdammten Arsch versohlen werde. tell him I'm gonna nail his fucking ass.
告诉他我要揍他一顿。
Ich rufe dich an... später.
I'll call you...
Later.
稍后我会给你打电话。
Seine Frau. Dieser Typ sagt, sie wurde letzten Mittwoch entführt.
His wife.
This guy says she was kidnapped last Wednesday.
他的妻子。这家伙说她上周三被绑架了。
Der Tag unserer Morde.
The day of our homicides.
我们发生凶杀案的那一天。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Und wer war dieser Typ?
And this guy was who?
这家伙是谁？
Der Buchhalter von Lundegaards Schwiegervater.
Lundegaard's father-in-law's accountant.
伦德高的岳父的会计师。
Gustafsons Buchhalter.
Gustafson's accountant.
古斯塔夫森的会计师。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Aber wir haben Gustafson immer noch nicht gefunden?
But we still haven't found Gustafson?
但我们还没找到古斯塔夫森？
...sehen...
...looking...
...看...
Entschuldige. Habe es nicht mitbekommen, Lou.
Sorry. Didn't copy, Lou.
抱歉。没有抄袭，卢。
Wird immer noch vermisst. Wir suchen.
Still missing.
We're looking.
仍下落不明。我们正在寻找。
Kopie. Und Lundegaard. zu?
Copy.
And Lundegaard. too?
复制。还有伦德加德。也？
Ja. Wo bist du, Margie?
Yeah.
Where are you. Margie?
是的。你在哪里？玛吉？
Ich bin fast zurück.
I'm almost back.
我快回来了。
Ich fahre um den Moose Lake herum.
I'm taking a drive around Moose Lake.
我正在驾车绕穆斯湖行驶。
Gary ist ein Großmaul.
Gary's loudmouth.
加里 (Gary) 的大声喧哗。
Ja, das Großmaul.
Yeah, the loudmouth.
是啊，大嘴巴。
Also hat es der ganze Staat, was?
So the whole state has it, huh?
所以整个州都有了，是吧？
Gustafson und Lundegaard?
Gustafson and Lundegaard?
古斯塔夫森和伦德加德？
Ja, es ist über die Leitung.
Yeah.
It's over the wire.
是的。是通过网络进行的。
Es ist überall. Sie werden sie finden.
It's everywhere.
They'll find them.
它无处不在。他们会找到它们的。
Kopie.
Copy.
复制。
Ja, wir haben einen Hinweis dazu ...
Yeah, we got a lead on this...
是的，我们得到了这方面的线索……
Da ist das Auto! Da ist das Auto!
There's the car!
车就在那儿！车就在那儿！
Wessen Auto?
Whose car?
谁的车？
Mein Auto! Mein Auto! So nah! So nah!
My car! My car!
Tan Cierra! Tan Cierra!
我的車！我的車！很接近了！很接近了！
Okay. Vorsicht, Margie. Ich schicke ein paar Autos.
Okay. Careful. Margie.
I'll send a couple cars.
好的。小心点。玛吉。我会派几辆车过来。
Polizei!
Police!
警察！
Hände hoch!
Hands up!
举起手来！
Polizei!
Police!
警察！
Polizei!
Police!
警察！
Das war also Frau Lundegaard, die da auf dem Boden lag.
So that was Mrs. Lundegaard on the floor in there.
原来，那位坐在地板上的就是伦德加德夫人。
Und ich schätze, das war Ihr Komplize im Holzhäcksler.
And I guess that was your accomplice in the wood chipper.
我猜那个人就是你在木材削片机里的同伙。
Und diese drei Leute in Brainerd.
And those three people in Brainerd.
还有布雷纳德的那三个人。
Und wofür?
And for what?
那是为了什么呢？
Für ein kleines Geld.
For a little bit of money.
为了一点点钱。
Es gibt im Leben mehr als nur ein bisschen Geld, wissen Sie?
There's more to life than a little money, you know?
你知道吗，生活中除了金钱以外还有很多其他的东西。
Weißt du das nicht?
Don't you know that?
你不知道吗？
Und hier sind Sie.
And here you are.
你在这里。
Und es ist ein wunderschöner Tag.
And it's a beautiful day.
今天真是美好的一天。
Also...
Well...
出色地...
Ich verstehe es einfach nicht.
I just don't understand it.
我就是不明白。
Herr Anderson?
Mr. Anderson?
安德森先生？
WHO?
Who?
WHO？
Mr. Anderson, ist das hier Ihr burgunderfarbener 98er?
Mr. Anderson, is this your burgundy '98 out here?
安德森先生，这是您 1998 年的勃艮第葡萄酒吗？
Einen Moment.
Just a sec.
稍等一下。
Könnten Sie bitte die Tür öffnen?
Could you open the door, please?
请你开一下门好吗？
Ja, ja, nur eine Sekunde.
Yeah, yeah, just a sec.
是的，是的，稍等一下。
Einen Moment.
Just a sec.
稍等一下。
- Dale! - Mein Bein!
- Dale!
- My leg!
- 戴尔！- 我的腿！
NEIN!
No!
不！
Sie haben es angekündigt.
They announced it.
他们宣布了这一消息。
Sie haben es angekündigt?
They announced it?
他们宣布了？
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Also?
So?
所以？
Drei-Cent-Briefmarke.
Three-cent stamp.
三美分邮票。
Deine Stockente?
Your mallard?
你的野鸭？
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Das ist großartig.
That's terrific.
太棒了。
Es sind nur drei Cent.
It's just a three-cent.
只不过是三分钱而已。
Es ist großartig.
It's terrific.
太棒了。
Hautmans Blauflügelente bekam die 29 Cent.
Hautman's blue-winged teal got the 29-Cent.
霍特曼 (Hautman) 的蓝翅绿头鸭获得了 29 美分。
Die Leute verwenden die Drei-Cent-Münze nicht oft.
People don't much use the three-cent.
人们不怎么使用三分钱。
Oh, für Pete’s … Natürlich tun sie das.
Oh, for Pete's...
Of course they do.
哦，对于 Pete's...他们当然会这么做。
Immer wenn sie das Porto erhöhen,
Whenever they raise the postage,
每当他们提高邮费时，
Die Leute brauchen die kleinen Briefmarken. people need the little stamps.
人们需要小邮票。
Ja?
Yeah?
是的？
Wenn sie mit einem Haufen der Alten festsitzen.
When they're stuck with a bunch of the old ones.
当他们被一堆旧的事物困住时。
Ja.
Yeah.
是的。
Ich schätze.
I guess.
我想是的。
Das ist großartig. Ich bin so stolz auf dich, Norm.
That's terrific.
I'm so proud of you, Norm.
太棒了。我为你感到骄傲，诺姆。
Verdammt, Norm, weißt du, uns geht es ziemlich gut.
Heck, Norm, you know, we're doing pretty good.
哎呀，诺姆，你知道，我们做得很好。
Ich liebe dich, Margie.
I love you, Margie.
我爱你，玛吉。
Ich liebe dich, Norm.
I love you, Norm.
我爱你，诺姆。
Noch zwei Monate.
Two more months.
再过两个月。
Noch zwei Monate.
Two more months.
再过两个月。